Okay hi everyone.
好的，大家好。
Let's get started again.
让我们重新开始吧。
Um. Okay. So, first of all for a couple of announcements.
嗯。好的。所以，首先要发布几个公告。
Um, first of all thanks to everyone, um,
嗯，首先要感谢大家，嗯，
who filled in our mid-quarter survey we've actually gotten,
谁填写了我们实际得到的季度中期调查，
um, great participation in that.
嗯，很好地参与其中。
Here are my two little Pac-Man figures.
这是我的两个小吃家伙人物。
So, the Pac-Man figures thinks,
所以，吃豆人的数字认为，
means that almost everyone thinks the lectures are at
意味着几乎所有人都认为讲座是在
the right pace and those that don't are pretty much evenly divided.
正确的节奏和那些没有的节奏几乎是平均分配的。
Um, if we go for how challenging was Assignment three,
嗯，如果我们选择具有挑战性的是作业三，
slightly more people thought it was too easy than too hard.
稍微多一些人认为这太容易而不是太难。
So, I guess we're setting about rectifying that with
所以，我想我们正在着手纠正这个问题
assignments four and five, um, [NOISE].
作业四和五，嗯，[NOISE]。
So, though there are a whole bunch of other questions and we've
所以，虽然还有很多其他问题，但我们已经做到了
been trying to absorb all the feedback.
一直试图吸收所有的反馈。
I mean one of the questions was what people wanted most from the remaining lectures.
我的意思是其中一个问题是人们在剩下的讲座中最想要的。
I guess the good news here is really we're very good at predicting, um,
我想这里的好消息是我们非常擅长预测，嗯，
what people wanted, that or else everybody
人们想要什么，或者每个人
just looked ahead in the syllabus and wrote down what it said was
只是在教学大纲中向前看并写下它所说的内容
ahead in the syllabus but I guess the most popular four answers to
在教学大纲中提前，但我想最受欢迎的四个答案
topics that they wanted in the remaining lectures were Transformers and BERT,
他们在剩下的讲座中想要的主题是变形金刚和BERT，
both of which are gonna be covered this week.
这两个都将在本周被覆盖。
Uh, question-answering which we talked about last week, um,
呃，上周我们谈过的问答，嗯，
and then text generation and summarization
然后是文本生成和摘要
and you guys get Abby back next week to talk about that.
你们下周要回Abby谈论这件事。
Um, there are also a lot of people also answered this question
嗯，也有很多人也回答了这个问题
a different way as to what kind of style of stuff,
关于什么样的东西，不同的方式，
um, some people emphasized new research and the latest updates from the field.
嗯，有些人强调新的研究和该领域的最新更新。
I guess we'll get some of that today as well,
我想我们今天也会得到一些，
some people are more interested in
有些人对此感兴趣
successful applications in industry or trying to do a bit of that,
在工业中成功应用或尝试做一些，
um, cool new neural architectures.
嗯，很酷的新神经架构。
Um, the bottom answer wasn't the most popular one,
嗯，最底层的答案不是最受欢迎的答案，
I'll admit but at least a few people, um,
我承认，但至少有几个人，嗯，
wish that we were teaching more linguistic stuff.
希望我们教授更多语言学的东西。
Um, I mean that is something that I actually feel
嗯，我的意思是这是我真正感受到的
a bit awkward about the way things were merged with CS224N,
关于事物与CS224N合并的方式有点尴尬，
with this deep learning,
通过深入学习，
I mean the truth of the matter is that sort of seems
我的意思是事情的真相就是这样
like in the early part of the course,
就像在课程的早期阶段一样
there's so much to cover with,
有很多东西可以覆盖，
um, neural networks, backpropagation,
嗯，神经网络，反向传播，
different, um, neural net architectures and so on that the reality is that we
不同的，嗯，神经网络架构等现实就是我们
teach rather less linguistic stuff than we used to in the class.
比我们在课堂上学习的语言学习要少得多。
I mean, for the last four weeks of the class we really do try and
我的意思是，在课程的最后四周，我们确实尝试过
cover some more linguistic stuff topics.
涵盖一些更多的语言主题。
Um, so look forward to that.
嗯，所以期待那样。
Um, announcements.
嗯，公告。
Okay. So we've made a couple of deadline changes.
好的。所以我们做了几个截止日期的修改。
Um, firstly, a number of people have
嗯，首先，一些人有
mentioned that they think assignment five is a bit tough.
提到他们认为任务五有点难。
And so, we're giving people one extra day,
所以，我们给人们额外的一天，
um, to do assignment five.
嗯，做任务五。
Um, I'm realizing in one sense that one extra day is not a ton
嗯，我在某种意义上意识到，额外的一天不是一吨
but you know there's sort of this complex balance here because on the other hand,
但是你知道这里有这种复杂的平衡，因为另一方面，
we don't really want to undermine time that people have available for final projects.
我们真的不想破坏人们可用于最终项目的时间。
And if you're one of the people who hasn't yet started assignment five,
如果你是尚未开始任职的人之一，
um, we do really encourage you to get underway on it.
嗯，我们真的鼓励你继续它。
Um, yeah, in the reverse direction
嗯，是的，反方向
we decided that the project milestone was really too late.
我们认为项目的里程碑真的太晚了。
If we are going to be able to give you feedback on it that you could usefully make use
如果我们能够为您提供反馈，您可以使用它
of, so we're moving the project milestone date two days earlier.
因此，我们提前两天将项目里程碑日期移动了。
And so, we've also gotten everyone's project proposals and our
所以，我们也得到了每个人的项目提案和我们的
planned hope is to get them back to everybody on Friday.
计划好的希望是让他们在星期五回到每个人身上。
Yes, so, a lot of things moving.
是的，所以，很多事情都在发生变化。
Um, and finally on other announcements I guess, um, on
嗯，最后我猜其他公告，嗯，嗯
this Thursday is our first invited speaker, um, and so,
这个星期四是我们第一个受邀的演讲者，嗯，等等，
if you're in person student you're meant to be here,
如果你是面对面的学生，你本来就是在这里，
um, and if you're not able to be here,
嗯，如果你不能在这里，
you should know about our reaction paragraph policy and
你应该知道我们的反应段落政策和
I actually stuck up on the Piazza pinned posts about, um,
我实际上是在广场上固定的帖子，嗯，
reaction pieces and attendance, an example of a reaction piece, um,
反应片和出勤，一个反应片的例子，嗯，
from a past class to make it a little bit more concrete what's expected there.
来自过去的课程，使其更加具体，在那里期待什么。
But, you know, the idea is what we're hoping for something that isn't a ton of work.
但是，你知道，这个想法是我们希望的东西，而不是大量的工作。
You can just write 100, 150 words, a few sentences,
你可以写100,150字，几句话，
but wanting you to pick out a specific thing that was
但是想要你挑出一个特定的东西
interesting and write a couple of sentences
有趣，写几句话
about what it was and what your thoughts are about it.
关于它是什么以及你对它的看法。
I, not just some very generic statement of this was a lecture about transformers.
我，不仅仅是一些非常通用的声明是关于变形金刚的讲座。
He talked about transformers and it was interesting,
他谈到了变形金刚这很有意思，
that is not what we want for the reaction piece. Um, okay.
这不是我们想要的反应片。嗯，好的。
So, here's the plan for today.
所以，这是今天的计划。
So, for today's, what I want to talk about is,
那么，对于今天来说，我想谈的是，
um, the exciting recent work about contextual word representations.
嗯，关于语境词表示的最近令人兴奋的工作。
I mean I, I was thinking of what I was gonna say I was wanting to say, oh, this is
我的意思是我，我想的是我要说的是我想要说的，哦，这是
the most exciting thing in deep learning for NLP in
NLP深度学习中最激动人心的事情
the last five years then something's just completely wrong,
在过去的五年里，有些事情完全错了，
because really this is the most exciting thing in deep learning that happened in 2018.
因为这是2018年发生的深度学习中最激动人心的事情。
I mean, I guess things move very quickly, um,
我的意思是，我觉得事情发展很快，嗯，
in deep learning at the moment and it's sort of I don't think it's
目前在深度学习中，我认为不是这样
really fair to say that you know it's got 5 years of life.
非常公平地说，你知道它有5年的生命。
But there's a very exciting thing that happened last year,
但是去年发生了一件令人兴奋的事情，
and we'll talk about that.
我们会谈论这个。
Okay. So, we'll talk about early stuff,
好的。那么，我们将讨论早期的东西，
the ELMo, ULMfit,
ELMo，ULMfit，
transformer architectures briefly and then go on to
变压器架构简要然后继续
talk about the BERT model that's being quite prominent lately.
谈谈最近非常突出的BERT模型。
So, let's just recap,
那么，让我们回顾一下，
let's just go backwards a bit first to think about, um,
让我们先回顾一下，嗯，
where we've been and where we are now and why we might want something more.
我们去过的地方和现在的地方以及为什么我们可能想要更多的东西。
So, up until now,
所以，到现在为止，
we've sort of just had,
我们有点刚才，
one representation for words which is what we learned at the beginning of class,
我们在课程开始时学到的单词表示，
there was a word, you trained a word vector for it and that's what you used in your model.
有一个词，你训练了一个单词向量，这就是你在模型中使用的。
Um, and you could do that, with algorithms like Word2vec,
嗯，你可以用Word2vec等算法做到这一点，
GloVe, or fastText that I mentioned last week.
我上周提到的GloVe或fastText。
Um, so some on this sort of progression of ideas in deep learning,
嗯，所以有些关于深度学习的这种思想进展，
when deep learning for NLP or the general
当深入学习NLP或一般时
just the resurgence of neural networks for NLP
只是NLP神经网络的复兴
came about sort of at the beginning of this decade.
在这个十年的开始出现了一些问题。
Um, these pre-trained word vectors.
嗯，这些预先训练过的单词向量。
So, pre-trained unsupervised over a large amount of text.
因此，预训练无人监督大量文本。
They were completely seen as the secret sauce,
他们完全被视为秘密酱，
and they were the thing that transformed
他们就是改变了的东西
neural networks from NLP to something that didn't really work,
从NLP到无法正常工作的神经网络，
to something that worked great.
做的很棒。
Um, so, this is actually an old slide of mine.
嗯，所以，这实际上是我的一张旧幻灯片。
So, this is a slide I guess I first made for
所以，这是我想我第一次制作的幻灯片
2012 ACL tutorial and then sort of used in lectures.
2012年ACL教程然后在讲座中使用。
Sort of in 2013, 2014. Um-.
排序在2013年，2014年。嗯 - 。
And so this was sort of the picture in those years.
所以这就是那些年来的情况。
So this was looking at two tasks,
所以这是在看两个任务，
part of speech tagging and named entity recognition which I'll use quite a bit today.
我将在今天使用相当多的语音标记和命名实体识别。
And, you know, the top line was showing a state of the art which was
而且，你知道，最重要的是展示了最先进的技术
a traditional categorical feature based classifier of the kind
一种传统的基于分类特征的分类器
that dominated NLP in the 2000s decade, in their performance.
在他们的表现中，在2000年代的十年间主导了NLP。
And what then the next line showed is that if you took the same data set
然后下一行显示的是，如果你采用相同的数据集
and you trained a supervised neural network on it and said how good is your performance?
你训练了一个有监督的神经网络，并说你的表现有多好？
Um, the story was, it wasn't great.
嗯，故事是，它不是很好。
Um, part-of-speech tagging has very high numbers always for various reasons.
嗯，词性标注总是出于各种原因而具有非常高的数字。
So perhaps the more indicative one to look at is these named entity recognition numbers.
因此，或许更具指示性的是这些命名实体识别数字。
So, you know, this was sort of neural net sucked, right?
所以，你知道，这是一种神经网络，对吗？
The reason why last decade everybody used, um,
上个十年每个人都用过的原因，嗯，
categorical feature based, you know,
基于分类特征，你知道，
CRF, SVM kind of classifiers.
CRF，SVM类分类器。
Well, if you look, it worked eight percent better than a neural network.
好吧，如果你看，它比神经网络好8％。
Why wouldn't anybody?
为什么不会有人？
But then what had happened was people had come up with this idea that we could
但接下来发生的事情是人们想出了我们可以做到的这个想法
do unsupervised pre-training of word representations,
做无人监督的单词表示训练，
um, to come up with word vectors for words.
嗯，想出单词的单词向量。
And, you know, in those days,
而且，你知道，在那些日子里，
this was very hard to do the alg- both because of
由于这个原因，这很难做到
the kind of algorithms and the kind of machines that were available, right?
那种算法和可用的机器种类，对吧？
So Collobert and Weston, 2011,
所以Collobert和Weston，2011年，
spent seven weeks training their unsupervised word representations.
花了七个星期训练他们无人监督的单词表示。
And at the end of the day,
并在一天结束时，
there are only 100 dimensional, um, word representations.
只有100维，嗯，字表示。
But this was the miracle breakthrough, right?
但这是奇迹般的突破，对吧？
You've put in this miracle breakthrough of unsupervised word representations.
你已经把无监督的单词表示带入了这个奇迹般的突破。
And now, the neural net is getting to 88,87.
而现在，神经网络已达到88,87。
So it's almost as good as the feature-based classifier,
所以它几乎和基于特征的分类器一样好，
and then like any good engineers,
然后像任何优秀的工程师一样
they did some hacking with some extra features,
他们做了一些黑客攻击和一些额外的功能，
because they had some stuff like that.
因为他们有类似的东西。
And they got a system that was then slightly better than the feature based system.
他们得到的系统比基于功能的系统略胜一筹。
Okay. So that was sort of our picture that,
好的。这就是我们的照片，
um, having these pre-trained,
嗯，有这些预先训练过的，
unsuper- and unsupervised manner of word representations,
无表情和无监督的单词表示方式，
that was sort of the big breakthrough and
这是一个重大突破
the secret sauce that gave all the oomph that made,
秘密的酱汁，给了所有的魅力，
um, neural networks competitive.
嗯，神经网络竞争激烈。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
it's a sort of a funny thing happened which was after people had sort of had
这是一种有趣的事情发生在人们曾经有过之后
some of these initial breakthroughs which were
其中一些最初的突破是
all about unsupervised methods for pre-training,
所有关于无人监督的预训练方法，
it was the same in vision.
在视觉上是一样的。
This was the era in vision,
这是视觉时代，
where you were building restricted Boltzmann machines and doing
你在哪里建造受限制的Boltzmann机器并做
complicated unsupervised pre-training techniques on them as well.
它们也是复杂的无监督预训练技术。
Some- somehow, after people had kind of discovered that and started to get good on it,
某些人 - 某种程度上，在人们发现并且开始变得更好之后，
people sort of started to discover, well,
人们开始发现，好吧，
actually we have some new technologies for non-linearities,
实际上我们有一些非线性的新技术，
regularization, and things like that.
正规化等等。
And if we keep using those same technologies,
如果我们继续使用相同的技术，
we can just go back to good old supervised learning.
我们可以回到良好的老监督学习。
And shockingly, it works way better now inside neural networks.
令人震惊的是，它现在在神经网络中更好地工作。
And so if you sort of go ahead to what I will call,
所以如果你继续我会打电话，
sort of 2014 to 2018 picture,
从2014年到2018年的图片，
the, the picture is actually very different.
，图片实际上是非常不同的。
So the picture is, so this,
所以图片是，所以这个，
the results I'm actually gonna show you this is from the Chen and Manning,
结果我实际上会告诉你这是来自陈和曼宁，
um, neural dependency parser that we talked about weeks ago.
嗯，我们几周前谈过的神经依赖解析器。
The picture there was, um,
那张照片，嗯，
and you could- despite the fact that
你可以 - 尽管事实如此
this dependency parser is being trained on a pretty small corpus,
这个依赖解析器正在一个非常小的语料库上训练，
a million words of supervised data,
一百万字的监督数据，
you can just initialize it with random word vectors,
你可以用随机单词向量初始化它，
um, and train a dependency parser.
嗯，训练一个依赖解析器。
And to a first approximation,
并且到了第一个近似值，
it just works fine.
它只是工作正常。
You get, get sort of a 90 percent accuracy,
你得到了90％的准确率，
E- um, English dependency parser.
E- um，英语依赖解析器。
Now, it is the case that instead,
现在，情况就是这样，
you could use pre-trained word embeddings and you do a bit better.
你可以使用经过预先训练的单词嵌入，你会做得更好。
You do about one percent better.
你做得好一个百分点。
And so this was sort of the,
所以这就是，
the new world order which was yeah, um,
新的世界秩序，是的，嗯，
these pre-trained unsupervised word embeddings are useful because you can
这些预先训练过的无监督词嵌入很有用，因为你可以
train them from a lot more data and they can know about a much larger vocabulary.
从更多的数据中训练他们，他们可以知道更大的词汇量。
That means they are useful.
这意味着它们很有用。
They help with rare words and things like that and they give you a percent,
他们帮助处理罕见的单词和类似的东西，他们给你一个百分比，
but they're definitely no longer the sort of night and day,
但他们绝对不再是那种日夜，
uh, thing to make neural networks work that we used to believe.
呃，让神经网络工作的东西，我们曾经相信。
I'm, I'm just gonna deviate here to,
我，我只是偏离这里，
from the main narrative to just sort of say, um,
从主要的叙述到只是说，嗯，
one more tip for dealing with unknown words with word vectors,
用词向量处理未知单词的另一个提示，
um, just in case it's useful for some people,
嗯，以防它对某些人有用，
building question answering systems, right?
建立问答系统吧？
So, um, so for sort of word vectors on unknown words, you know,
所以，嗯，所以对于未知单词的单词向量，你知道，
the commonest thing historically is you've got your supervised training data,
历史上最常见的事情是你有受监督的训练数据，
you define a vocab which might be words that occur
你定义一个词汇，可能是出现的词
five times or more in your supervised training data.
在您的监督培训数据中五次或更多次。
And you treat everything else as an UNK.
而你把其他一切当作一个UNK来对待。
And so you also train one vector per UNK.
因此，您还可以根据UNK训练一个向量。
Um, but that has some problems which you have no way to
嗯，但这有一些你无法解决的问题
distinguish different UNK words either for identity or meaning.
区分不同的UNK词语的身份或意义。
And that tends to be problematic for question answering systems.
这对问答系统来说往往是个问题。
And so one way to fix that is what we talked about last week,
所以解决这个问题的一种方法是我们上周谈到的，
you just say, "Oh, words are made out of characters.
你只是说，“哦，文字是由人物组成的。
I can use character representations to learn word vectors for other words."
我可以使用字符表示来学习其他单词的单词向量。“
And you can certainly do that.
你当然可以做到这一点。
You might wanna try that.
你可能想尝试一下。
That adds some complexity.
这增加了一些复杂性。
Um, but especially for things like question answering systems,
嗯，尤其是像问答系统这样的东西，
there are a couple of other things that you can do
还有其他一些你可以做的事情
that work considerably better and they've been
那工作得相当好，他们一直都是
explored in this paper by Dhingra et al., um, from 2017.
Dhingra等人在2017年从本文中探讨了这个问题。
Um, the first one is to say, well, um,
嗯，第一个就是说，嗯，嗯，
when you at test-time encounter new words, probably your unsupervised word,
当你在考试时遇到新单词，可能是你的无监督单词，
pre-trained word embeddings have a much bigger vocabulary than your actual system does.
预先训练的单词嵌入比你的实际系统有更大的词汇量。
So anytime you come across a word that isn't in
所以，每当你遇到一个不在的单词时
your vocab but is in the pre-trained word embeddings,
你的词汇，但是在预先训练过的单词嵌入中，
just use, get the word vector of that word and start using it.
只需使用，获取该单词的单词向量并开始使用它。
That'll be a much more useful thing to use.
这将是一个更有用的东西。
And then there's a second possible tip that if you
然后还有第二个可能的提示，如果你
see something that's still an unknown word,
看到一些仍然是一个未知单词的东西，
rather than treating it as UNK,
而不是将其视为UNK，
you just assign it on the spot,
你只需当场分配，
a random word vector.
随机单词向量。
And so this has the effect that each word does get a unique identity.
因此，这会产生每个单词确实获得唯一身份的效果。
Which means if you see the same word in the question,
这意味着如果你在问题中看到相同的单词，
and a potential answer,
和一个潜在的答案，
they will match together beautifully in an accurate way which you're
它们将以精确的方式精美地匹配在一起
not getting with just UNK matching and those can be kind of useful ideas to try.
没有与UNK匹配，这些可能是一些有用的想法尝试。
Okay, end digression. Okay, so up until now,
好的，结束题外话。好的，直到现在，
we just sort of had this representation of words,
我们只是有这种表达方式，
we ran Word2vec and we got a word vector,
我们运行了Word2vec，我们得到了一个单词向量，
um, for each word.
嗯，对于每个单词。
Um, so, um, that, that was useful.
嗯，嗯，那，这很有用。
It's worked pretty well.
它工作得很好。
Um, but it had, um,
嗯，但它有，嗯，
some big problems. So what were the big problems of doing that?
一些大问题。那么这样做的主要问题是什么？
The problems when we,
我们的问题，
of having a word vector in each word, yes.
在每个单词中都有一个单词向量，是的。
A lot of words have like one spelling, but a whole bunch of meanings.
很多单词都有一个拼写，但有很多含义。
Right, so, a word can have- So, typically,
是的，所以，一个词可以有 - 所以，通常，
you have one string of letters which has a whole bunch of meanings.
你有一串字母，里面有很多含义。
So, words have a ton of senses.
所以，言语有很多感官。
Um, and yeah, so that's
嗯，是的，所以那是
the biggest and most obvious problem that we're
我们遇到的最大和最明显的问题
collapsing together all the meanings of words.
将所有词语的含义折叠起来。
So, we talked about a bit where
所以，我们谈了一下
one solution to that was you could distinguish
一个解决方案是你可以区分
word senses and to have different word vectors for them.
单词感觉并为他们提供不同的单词向量。
Um, and I then said something about also you could think of
嗯，然后我说了一些关于你能想到的事情
this word vector as a sort of a mixture of them and maybe your model could separate it.
这个单词矢量作为它们的混合物，也许你的模型可以将它分开。
But it seems like we might want to take that more seriously.
但似乎我们可能想要更严肃地对待它。
And one way, um,
还有一种方式，嗯，
that we could take that more seriously is we could start to say, well,
我们可以更认真地对待，我们可以开始说，好吧，
really, you know, traditional lists of word senses are themselves a crude approximation.
实际上，你知道，传统的词义列表本身就是粗​​略的近似。
What we actually want to know is the sense of the word inside a particular context of use.
我们实际想知道的是在特定使用环境中的单词意义。
And sort of what I mean by that is, you know,
我的意思是，你知道，
we distinguish different senses of a word, right?
我们区分一个词的不同意义，对吧？
Say for the word star there's the astronomical sense and
对于明星这个词来说，有天文感和
there's the Hollywood sense and they're clearly different.
这是好莱坞的感觉，他们显然是不同的。
But you know, if we then go to this what I'm calling the Hollywood sense,
但是你知道，如果我们再去看看我称之为好莱坞的感觉，
I could then say, well, wait a minute.
我可以说，好吧，等一下。
There are movie stars and there are rock stars,
有电影明星，还有摇滚明星，
and there, uh, are R&amp;B stars,
那里，呃，是R＆B明星，
and there are country stars.
还有乡村明星。
Now, all of those different senses, um,
现在，所有这些不同的感官，嗯，
in certain contexts, though, one or other of them would be evoked.
但是，在某些情况下，会引发其中一个或另一个。
And so, you know,
所以，你知道，
it's very hard if you're trying to actually enumerate
如果你想要实际枚举，那就太难了
senses of a word as to which ones count as different or the same.
一个词的感觉，哪些被认为是不同的或相同的。
So, it's really you sort of wanna know what a word means in a context.
所以，你真的想知道一个词在上下文中意味着什么。
There's a second limitation of these word vectors which is,
这些单词向量的第二个限制是，
we haven't really talked about and is less obvious,
我们还没有真正谈过而且不太明显，
but it's also something that we might want to fix, and at least one of
但它也是我们可能想要修复的东西，至少有一个
the models we discussed today takes some aim at that,
我们今天讨论的模型有一些目标，
and that is, we just sort of have one vector for a word.
也就是说，我们只是有一个单词的向量。
But there are sort of different dimensions of a word.
但是一个词有不同的维度。
So, words can have different meanings,
所以，单词可以有不同的含义，
some sort of real semantics or words can have
某种真实的语义或文字可以有
different syntactic behavior like different parts of speech or grammatical behavior.
不同的句法行为，如不同的词性或语法行为。
So, in some sense, arrive and arrival,
所以，从某种意义上说，到达和到达，
their semantics are almost the same,
他们的语义几乎相同，
but they're different parts of speech.
但它们是不同的词性。
One is a, um, a verb and one is a noun,
一个是嗯，动词，一个是名词，
so they can kind of appear in quite different places.
所以它们可以出现在完全不同的地方。
And you know, you'd wanna do different things with them in a dependency parser.
而且你知道，你想在依赖解析器中用它们做不同的事情。
And there are even other dimensions.
甚至还有其他方面。
So, words also have register and connotation differences.
所以，单词也有注册和内涵的差异。
So, you can probably think of lots of different words for a bathroom,
所以，你可能会想到浴室有很多不同的词，
and a lot of those words all means semantically the same,
而且很多这些词在语义上都是一样的，
but have rather different registers and
但是有相当不同的寄存器和
connotations as to when they're appropriate to use.
关于什么时候它们适合使用的内涵。
And so, we might want to distinguish words on that basis as well.
因此，我们可能也希望在此基础上区分单词。
And so these are the kinds of soluti- things we want to
所以这些是我们想要的解决方案
solve with our new contextual word embeddings.
用我们新的上下文单词嵌入来解决。
Um, so I've said up until now, you know,
嗯，所以我说到现在为止，你知道，
oh, we just had these word vectors that we use,
哦，我们刚刚使用了这些单词向量，
words just had one vector.
单词只有一个向量。
Um, but if you actually think about it, maybe that's wrong.
嗯，但如果你真的想到它，也许这是错的。
I mean, maybe we never had a problem, or at any rate, we solved it six classes ago.
我的意思是，也许我们从来没有遇到过问题，或者无论如何，我们在六个班级之前解决了这个问题。
Because if you remember back, [NOISE] um,
因为如果你还记得，[NOISE]嗯，
to when we started talking about neural language models,
当我们开始谈论神经语言模型时，
well, what did a neural language model do?
那么，神经语言模型做了什么？
At the bottom, you fed into it the word vectors.
在底部，你输入了单词vector。
But then you ran across that one or more recurrent layers,
但是你遇到了一个或多个复发层，
something like a LSTM layer,
类似于LSTM层，
and it was calculating these representations that sit above each word and,
它正在计算这些表示位于每个单词之上的，
you know, the role of those hidden states is a bit ambivalent.
你知道，这些隐藏状态的作用有点矛盾。
They are used for prediction.
它们用于预测。
And they are used for next hidden state and output states and so on.
它们用于下一个隐藏状态和输出状态等。
But in many ways you can think huh,
但在很多方面，你可以想，呵呵，
these representations are actually representations of a word in context.
这些表示实际上是上下文中单词的表示。
And if you think about what happened with, uh,
如果你考虑一下发生了什么，呃，
the question answering systems,
问答系统，
that's exactly how they were used, right?
这正是他们的使用方式，对吗？
We ran LSTM's backwards and forwards,
我们向前和向后运行LSTM，
over a question in the passage, and then we say,
通过一个问题，然后我们说，
okay those are a good representation of a word's meaning and context.
好的，这些都是一个词的意义和背景的良好表现。
Let's start matching them with attention functions et cetera.
让我们开始将它们与注意力函数等相匹配。
So, it sort of seemed like we'd already invented a way to have,
所以，似乎我们已经发明了一种方法，
um, context-specific representations of words.
嗯，单词的特定于上下文的表示。
And effectively, you know,
你知道，实际上，
the rest of the content of this lecture is sort of basically no more complex than that.
本讲座的其他内容基本上没有那么复杂。
Um, that it took a while but sort of people woke up and started to notice, huh,
嗯，花了一段时间，但有些人醒来后开始注意到，呵呵，
really when you're running any language model,
当你运行任何语言模型时，
you generate a context-specific representation of words.
您生成一个特定于上下文的单词表示。
Maybe, if we just took those context-specific
也许，如果我们只是采取那些特定于上下文
representation of words, they'd be useful for doing other things with them.
对于单词的表示，它们对于用它们做其他事情是有用的。
And that's sort of, you know,
你知道，那就是那种
there are a few more details,
还有一些细节，
but that's really the summary of the entire of this lecture.
但这确实是整个讲座的总结。
Um, so one of the first things to do that was a paper that Matt Peters wrote in 2017,
嗯，所以要做的第一件事就是Matt Peters在2017年写的一篇论文，
um, the year before last.
嗯，前年。
Um, and this was sort of a predecessor to the sort of modern, um,
嗯，这有点像现代的前辈，嗯，
versions of, um, these context-sensitive word embeddings.
嗯，这些上下文敏感的单词嵌入的版本。
So, um, together with co-authors,
所以，嗯，和共同作者一起，
he came up with a paper called TagLM,
他想出了一篇名为TagLM的论文，
but it essentially already had all the main ideas.
但它基本上已经有了所有主要想法。
So, what, um, was wanted was okay.
那么，嗯，被通缉是好的。
We want to do better at tasks such as named-entity recognition.
我们希望在命名实体识别等任务中做得更好。
And what we'd like to do is know about the meaning of a word in context.
我们想要做的是了解一个词在上下文中的含义。
Um, but you know, standardly if we're doing named-entity recognition,
嗯，但是你知道，如果我们正在进行命名实体识别，
we just train it on half a million words of supervised data.
我们只训练了50万字的监督数据。
And that's not much of a source of
这并不是什么来源
information to be learning about the meaning of words and context.
要了解单词和语境的含义的信息。
So, why don't we adopt the semi-supervised approach and so that's what we do.
那么，为什么我们不采用半监督方法，这就是我们所做的。
So, we start off with a ton of unlabeled data.
因此，我们从大量未标记的数据开始。
Um, and from that unlabeled data,
嗯，从那些未标记的数据，
we can train a conventional word embedding model like Word2vec.
我们可以训练像Word2vec这样的传统单词嵌入模型。
But we can also at the same time train a neural language model.
但我们也可以同时训练神经语言模型。
So, something like a bi-LSTM language model.
所以，像bi-LSTM语言模型。
Okay. So, then for step two when we're using our supervised data,
好的。那么，当我们使用我们的监督数据时，对于第二步，
um, actually, I guess that's step three.
嗯，实际上，我猜这是第三步。
Okay. Um, so for then when we want to learn our supervised part-of-speech tagger at the top,
好的。嗯，那么当我们想要在顶部学习我们受监督的词性标注器时，
what we're gonna do is say, well,
我们要做的就是说，好吧，
for the input words New what York is located,
输入单词New New York所在的位置，
we can not only use the word embedding which is context independent,
我们不仅可以使用与上下文无关的单词嵌入，
but we can use our trained recurrent language model and also run it over this import,
但我们可以使用我们训练有素的循环语言模型，并在此导入中运行它，
and then we'll generate hidden states in our bi-LSTM language model and we can also
然后我们将在bi-LSTM语言模型中生成隐藏状态，我们也可以
feed those in as features into ou- our sequence tagging model,
将那些作为特征输入到我们的序列标记模型中，
and those features will let it work better.
而这些功能将让它更好地工作。
Here's a second picture that runs this through in much greater detail.
这是第二张图片，详细介绍了这一点。
So, so, we're assuming that we have trained, uh,
所以，我们假设我们已经训练过，呃，
bi-LSTM language model, um,
bi-LSTM语言模型，嗯，
on a lot of unsupervised data.
关于很多无人监督的数据。
Then what we wanna do is we want to do named entity recognition for New York is located.
那么我们想做的是我们想要为纽约做名为实体的识别。
So, the first thing we do is say,
所以，我们做的第一件事就是说，
let's just run New York is located through our separately trained neural language model.
让我们通过我们单独训练的神经语言模型来运行纽约。
So, we run it through a forward language model.
因此，我们通过前向语言模型运行它。
We run it through a backward language model.
我们通过后向语言模型运行它。
We get from that, um,
我们从中得到，嗯，
a hidden state representation,
一个隐藏的状态表示，
um, for each word,
嗯，对于每个单词，
we concatenate the forward and backward ones,
我们连接前进和后退的，
and that's going to give a set, a concatenated language model embedding
这将是一个集合，一个连接的语言模型嵌入
which we'll use as features in our named entity recognizer.
我们将在命名实体识别器中用作功能。
So, then for the named entity recognizer itself that we're gonna
那么，对于我们将要命名的实体识别器本身
train supervised while we have the same sentence,
在我们有相同的句子的情况下，我会监督
so we can both look up a Word2vec-style token embedding for it.
所以我们都可以为它查找Word2vec样式的标记嵌入。
We can use what we learned about with character level CNNs and RNNs and we can build
我们可以使用我们从字符级CNN和RNN中学到的知识，我们可以构建
a character level representation for it which we also
它的字符级别表示我们也是
concatenate to have two representations.
连接有两个表示。
So, we feed these representations into a bi-LSTM layer.
因此，我们将这些表示提供给bi-LSTM层。
But then when we get the output of the, this bi-LSTM layer,
但是当我们得到这个bi-LSTM层的输出时，
as well as this normal output,
以及这个正常输出，
we can concatenate with each output what was- what we get from our,
我们可以连接每个输出什么 - 我们从我们得到的，
um, neural language model.
嗯，神经语言模型。
So, each of these things becomes a pair of states.
所以，这些东西中的每一个都变成了一对状态。
One that's spit up from the first bi-LSTM layer and
一个从第一个双LSTM层吐出来的
then it's concatenated with something from the neural language model.
然后它与神经语言模型中的东西连接起来。
And so that concatenated representation is then fed into a second layer of bi-LSTM.
然后将连接的表示输入到第二层bi-LSTM中。
And then from the output of that,
然后从输出，
we do the usual kind of softmax classification
我们做了通常的softmax分类
where we're then giving tags like beginning of location,
然后我们在那里给出像开始位置的标签，
end of location, say New York is a location and then is, we'll get
位置结束，说纽约是一个位置，然后，我们会得到
another tag to say it's not a location. Does that makes sense?
另一个标签说它不是一个位置。这有道理吗？
Yeah so, um, so the central thing is
是的，嗯，所以最重要的是
sort of having seen that these sort of representations that we get from Bi-LSTMs are useful.
有点看到我们从Bi-LSTM获得的这些表示是有用的。
We're just going to feed them into supervised models as we train them,
我们训练它们时，我们只是将它们送入有监督的模型中，
and the idea is that will give us better features of words.
而这个想法将会给我们更好的词汇特征。
Some kind of representation of their meaning and context,
他们的意义和背景的某种表示，
which will allow us to learn better named entity recognizers or what it- whatever it is.
这将使我们能够学习更好的命名实体识别器或它是什么 - 无论它是什么。
Maybe I should put this slide earlier,
也许我应该提前放这张幻灯片，
but this slide was meant to remind you what a named entity recognizer is.
但这张幻灯片旨在提醒您命名的实体识别器是什么。
I hope you remember that,
我希望你记住那个，
something where are we going to find and label
我们将在哪里找到并贴上标签
entities for things like person, location, date, organization.
用于人，地点，日期，组织等事物的实体。
So anyway, doing this worked.
无论如何，这样做有效。
So, here's a little bit of a history.
所以，这里有一段历史。
So the most famous Named Entity Recognition dataset is this CoNLL 2003 dataset,
因此，最着名的命名实体识别数据集是此CoNLL 2003数据集，
which actually exists in multiple languages.
实际上存在多种语言。
But whenever people say CoNLL 2003 and don't mention a language,
但每当人们说CoNLL 2003并且没有提到语言时，
they mean the English version of it.
他们的意思是英文版。
That's the way the world works.
这就是世界的运作方式。
Um, okay so on this dataset- yeah.
嗯，好的，就这个数据集 - 是的。
So, it's sort of been around for whatever, 15 years roughly now.
所以，它现在已经存在了15年左右。
So, in the- so it was originally a competition, right?
所以，在 - 所以它最初是一场比赛，对吗？
So, this is in 2003 was the original bake-off.
所以，这是在2003年的原始烘烤。
My group actually took place in that.
我的小组实际上是在那里发生的。
Took part in it. I think we got third or fourth place or something,
参与其中。我想我们得到了第三或第四名，
and our F1 score was 86.
我们的F1得分是86。
The people who won were from IBM Research Labs,
赢得的人来自IBM研究实验室，
and they got 88 almost 89.
他们得到88分近89分。
But a difference between these two things is our system was
但这两件事之间的区别在于我们的系统
a single clean machine-learning model categorical,
一个干净的机器学习模型分类，
whereas the IBM one was not only an ensemble
而IBM的不仅仅是一个整体
of four different machine learning models, plus gazetteers.
四种不同的机器学习模型，加上地名录。
It also fit in the output of
它也适合于输出
two other old NER systems that IBM people were trained years ago on different data.
IBM员工多年前在不同数据上接受过培训的另外两个旧NER系统。
So it was- I guess it worked for them but,
所以它 - 我猜它对他们有用但是，
it was a fairly complex system.
这是一个相当复杂的系统。
Here's another system from Stanford.
这是斯坦福的另一个系统。
So this was our classic Stanford NER system that is widely used.
所以这是我们广泛使用的经典斯坦福NER系统。
So, this was then using a conditional random field model which generally dominated
因此，这是使用通常占主导地位的条件随机场模型
sort of the second half of the 2000s and the first half of the 2010s for doing NER,
有点像2000年代后半期和2010年上半年的做NER，
and it was sort of, you know, a bit but not usually better than the 2003 system.
你知道，有点但不一定比2003系统更好。
This system here was sort of the best ever built categorical CRF system.
这个系统是有史以来最好的分类CRF系统。
But rather than only using the training data to build the model as this system did,
但不是仅仅使用训练数据来构建该系统所做的模型，
it threw in Wikipedia and other stuff to make it work better,
它投入了维基百科和其他东西，使其更好地工作，
and that got you to about 90,8 F1.
这让你大约90,8 F1。
So, essentially, once sort of BiLSTM style models started to be known and used in NLP.
因此，基本上，一旦BiLSTM样式模型开始在NLP中被人们所知并使用。
That was when people were able to train, build training
那是人们能够训练，建立训练的时候
just on the training data systems that worked a lot better.
只是在训练数据系统上运行得更好。
Because essentially you're going from the same data from this system to that system.
因为基本上你从这个系统的相同数据到那个系统。
So, you're getting about 4 percent gain on it,
所以，你获得了大约4％的收益，
because it's not- wasn't making use of Wikipedia and things like that;
因为它不是 - 没有使用维基百科和类似的东西;
and so this Ma and Hovy system is pretty well-known getting about 91,21.
所以这个Ma和Hovy系统非常有名，大约91,21。
Okay, but if we then go to this TagLM system, um,
好的，但如果我们再去这个TagLM系统，嗯，
that Matt Peters and Co have a system that
Matt Peters和Co有一个系统
was sort of similar to the Ma and Hovy system that is a little bit worse.
有点像Ma和Hovy系统，有点差。
But the point is that this BiLSTM uses sorry- using the neural language model,
但关键是这个BiLSTM使用了抱歉 - 使用神经语言模型，
is just a useful oomph giver which sort of takes the results up.
只是一个有用的能力提供者，它会带来结果。
Yeah, not night and day but,
是的，不是白天和黑夜，但是，
slightly over a percent and then gives them the best NER system that was then available.
略高于百分之一，然后给他们最好的NER系统，然后可用。
So that sort of proved these sort of
所以这种证明了这一点
contextual word representations really had some power and started to be useful,
语境词表示真的有一些力量，并开始有用，
and then there's a white space at the top because we'll get back to more of this later.
然后在顶部有一个白色空间，因为我们稍后会回到更多。
Um, there's some details on their language model.
嗯，他们的语言模型有一些细节。
Some of their details are that it's useful to have
他们的一些细节是有用的
a bidirectional language model, not unidirectional.
双向语言模型，而不是单向的。
It's useful to have a big um,
有一个大的，有用的，
language model to get much in the way of gains,
语言模型可以获得很多收益，
um and, you need to train this language model over much more data.
嗯，你需要在更多的数据上训练这种语言模型。
It doesn't work if you're just sort of training it over your supervised training data.
如果您只是对您的监督培训数据进行培训，那么它就无法运行。
Another model that was around was CoVe,
另一个模特是CoVe，
but I think I'll skip that.
但我想我会跳过那个。
Okay. So, then the next year, um,
好的。那么，明年，嗯，
Matt Peters and a different set of colleagues
马特彼得斯和一组不同的同事
then came up with an improved system called ELMo,
然后提出了一个名为ELMo的改进系统，
and effectively this was the breakthrough system.
实际上这是突破性的系统。
That this was sort of just the system that everybody
这有点像每个人的系统
noticed and said "Wow these contextual word vectors are great.
注意到并说“哇这些上下文单词向量很棒。
Everyone should be using them,
每个人都应该使用它们，
not traditional word vectors." Yes?
不是传统的单词向量。“是吗？
I have a simple question, imagine re-training a system, what exactly
我有一个简单的问题，想象重新训练一个系统，到底是什么
what measure [inaudible]
什么措施[音频不清晰]
It's pre-trained because this piece over here;
它是预训练的，因为这件作品在这里;
a big neural language model is trained first,
首先训练一个大的神经语言模型，
and there's an important thing I forgot to say.
而且我忘了说一件重要的事情。
So, thank you for the question.
所以，谢谢你的提问。
The main reason why it's- in some sense pre-trained,
它在某种意义上是预训练的主要原因，
is this was trained first.
这是第一次训练。
But the main reason why people think of this as pre-training
但人们认为这是预训练的主要原因
is after you've trained this, it is frozen.
在你训练了之后，它被冻结了。
So, this is just something that you can run with parameters which will give
所以，这只是你可以使用参数运行的东西
you a vector which is your contextual word representation each position,
你是一个向量，它是每个位置的上下文单词表示，
and then that's just going to be used in this system.
然后，这将在这个系统中使用。
So, when you're training this system,
所以，当你训练这个系统时，
there's no gradient flowing back into
没有梯度流回来
this neural language model that's changing and updating it; it's just fixed.
这种神经语言模型正在改变和更新它;它刚刚修好了。
And so that's sort of the sense when people are talking about pre-training.
所以当人们谈论预训练时，这就是一种感觉。
It's sort of normally a model that you trained
它通常是你训练过的模特
somewhere else and that you're using to give features,
在其他地方，你用来提供功能，
but isn't part of the model that you are now training. Yeah?
但不是您正在训练的模型的一部分。是吗？
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Well, I guess that's, I wouldn't quite call it reconstruction.
嗯，我猜是的，我不会称之为重建。
Yeah, it's unsupervised in the sense that this is a language model,
是的，从某种意义上讲它是无人监督的，这是一种语言模型，
you're training it to predict the next word.
你正在训练它来预测下一个词。
So here are words one to k. What is the k plus oneth word during a cross entropy loss,
所以这里是一对一的话。在交叉熵损失期间k plus oneth字是什么，
and repeat over for each position.
并重复每个职位。
[NOISE] Yes, so I mean,
[NOISE]是的，所以我的意思是，
having gone through TagLM in some detail, I mean,
我的意思是，我已经详细介绍了TagLM，
in some sense, the difference between TagLM and ELMo is kind of small,
从某种意义上说，TagLM和ELMo之间的区别有点小，
it's sort of in the details.
这有点细节。
So I mean, to a first approximation,
所以我的意思是，对于第一个近似，
they're doing exactly the same again,
他们再次做同样的事，
but a little bit better.
但好一点。
Um, so, um, I sort of hope it made sense the last time,
嗯，所以，嗯，我希望它最后一次有意义，
I mean, what are the things that are different?
我的意思是，有什么不同的东西？
Um, they do the bidirectional language model a bit differently,
嗯，他们做双向语言模型有点不同，
and actually one of their concerns was to try and come up with
实际上他们关注的一个问题就是试图想出来
a compact language model that would be easy for people to use,
一个易于人们使用的紧凑语言模型，
um, in other tasks even if they don't have the beefiest computer hardware in the world.
嗯，在其他任务中，即使他们没有世界上最强大的计算机硬件。
And so they decided to dispense with having
所以他们决定放弃
word representations altogether and just use, um,
单词表示完全只是使用，嗯，
character CNNs to build word representations,
字符CNN构建单词表示，
because that lessens the number of parameters you have to store,
因为这减少了你必须存储的参数数量，
the big matrices you have to, um, use.
你必须使用的大矩阵，嗯，使用。
Um, they expanded the hidden dimension to 4,096,
嗯，他们将隐藏的维度扩展到4,096，
but then they project it down to
但后来他们把它投射到了
512 dimensions with a sort of feed-forward projection layer,
512个尺寸，带有一种前馈投影层，
and that's a fairly common technique to again reduce
这是一种相当常见的技术，可以再次减少
the parameterization of the model so that you have a lot of
模型的参数化使你有很多
parameters going in their current direction but you
参数在他们当前的方向但你
need much smaller matrices for including,
需要更小的矩阵来包括，
um, the input at the next level.
嗯，下一级的输入。
Um, between the layers,
嗯，层之间，
they now use a residual connection and they do a bit of parameter tying.
他们现在使用剩余连接，他们做了一些参数绑定。
So it's sort of all in the little details there.
所以在那里的细节中都是如此。
Um, but there's another interesting thing
嗯，但还有另外一件有趣的事情
that they did which was an important innovation of ELMo,
他们做了哪些是ELMo的重要创新，
so we should get this bit.
所以我们应该得到这一点。
So in TagLM,
所以在TagLM，
what was fed from the pre-trained LM into
什么从预先训练的LM喂养到
the main model was just the top level of the neural language model stack,
主模型只是神经语言模型堆栈的顶级，
and that was completely standard de rigueur in those days,
在那些日子里，这完全是标准的，
that you might have had three layers of
你可能有三层
neural language model that you regard at the top-level as your sort
您在顶级视为排序的神经语言模型
of one that's really captured the meaning of
一个真正捕捉到的意义
the sentence and the lower layers for processing that led up to it.
句子和较低层进行处理导致它。
Um, and they had the idea that maybe
嗯，他们有想法也许
it would be useful to actually use all layers of the,
实际使用的所有层是有用的，
biLSTM of the neural language models.
biLSTM的神经语言模型。
So maybe not just the top layer but all layers would be kind of useful.
所以也许不仅仅是顶层，而是所有层都有用。
So, um, there are these kind of complex equations,
所以，嗯，有这些复杂的方程，
uh, but essentially the point of it over here is,
呃，但基本上它在这里的意思是，
we going- for a particular position,
我们去一个特定的位置，
word seven in the language model,
语言模型中的第七个字，
we're going to take the hidden state at each level of our,
我们将在我们的每个级别采取隐藏状态，
our neural language model stack,
我们的神经语言模型堆栈，
we're going to give- learn a weight for that level,
我们要给 - 学习这个级别的重量，
we go in to sort of sum them,
我们进去总结一下，
so this is sort of a weighted average of the hidden layers at each position,
所以这是每个位置隐藏层的加权平均值，
and that will be used as our basic representation.
这将被用作我们的基本代表。
Um, and so, they found that that gave quite a bit
嗯，等等，他们发现这给了很多
of extra usefulness for- and different tasks could prefer different layers.
对于不同任务的额外有用性可能更喜欢不同的层。
There's one other bit here which is,
这里还有一点是，
they learn a global scaling factor Gamma for a particular task.
他们为特定任务学习全局比例因子Gamma。
And this allows them to control that for some tasks, the, um,
这允许他们控制某些任务，嗯，
contextual word embeddings might be really
语境词嵌入可能是真的
useful and for other tasks they might not be so useful,
有用的，对于其他任务，它们可能不那么有用，
so you're just sort of learning a specific,
所以你只是在学习一个特定的，
um, usefulness for the entire task.
嗯，对整个任务有用。
Okay. So, um, that's the sort of new version of language model.
好的。那么，嗯，这就是语言模型的新版本。
But this, this is allowing this idea of well,
但是，这是允许这个想法，
maybe there's sort of more syntactic meanings
也许还有更多的句法意义
of a word and more semantic meanings of a word,
一个单词和一个单词的更多语义含义，
possibly those could be represented at different layers of
可能那些可能代表不同的层次
your neural language model and then for
你的神经语言模型，然后为
different tasks you can differentially weight them.
不同的任务，你可以差异化他们。
Um, so that's the basic model.
嗯，这是基本模型。
So you run your biLSTM before to g et representations of each word.
所以你先运行你的biLSTM来表示每个单词。
And then the generic ELMo recipe was,
然后是通用的ELMo配方，
well, with that frozen language model,
好吧，用那种冷冻的语言模型，
you want to feed it into some supervised model depending on what the task was,
你想根据任务的内容将它喂入一些有监督的模型，
and they sort of say in the paper, well,
他们在论文中有点说，好吧，
how you do this maybe depends on the task.
你如何做到这一点可能取决于任务。
You might want to kind of concatenate it to the intermediate layer,
您可能希望将它连接到中间层，
just as the TagLM did,
正如TagLM所做的那样，
that might be fine.
这可能没事。
But you know it might also be useful to make use of
但是你知道使用它也可能有用
these ELMo representations when producing outputs,
这些ELMo表示在产生输出时，
so if you're doing something like a
所以，如果你正在做一些像
generation system or you might just sort of feed in the ELMo representation again,
生成系统，或者您可能只是再次输入ELMo表示，
be- before you sort of do the softmax to find the output,
be-在你做softmax之前找到输出，
they sort of left it flexible as to how it was used,
它们使它如何被使用变得灵活，
but the general picture,
但总的来说，
you know, was kinda like we saw before.
你知道，有点像我们之前看到的。
Indeed I'm reusing the same picture that you've calculated
事实上，我正在重复使用你计算过的相同图片
an ELMo representation for each position as a weighted average,
每个位置的ELMo表示作为加权平均值，
and then you're sort of concatenating that to the hidden state of
然后你有点把它连接到隐藏的状态
your supervised system and generating your output.
您的监督系统并生成您的输出。
And anyway, um, one way or another,
无论如何，嗯，不管怎样，
um, they were able to do this, uh,
嗯，他们能够做到这一点，呃，
and that with the little improvements that gave them about an extra
并且通过一些小的改进给了他们一个额外的
0,3 percent in Named Entity Recognition.
命名实体识别中的0,3％。
Um, now, that sort of sounds like not very much.
嗯，现在，这听起来不是很多。
And you might conclude from this why the excitement [LAUGHTER] and,
你可以从这里得出结论为什么兴奋[笑声]和
you know, in some sense, um,
你知道，从某种意义上说，嗯，
that's right because sort of to the extent that there was an interesting idea here really
这是正确的，因为在某种程度上真的有一个有趣的想法
that come up with it for the TagLM paper which gave a much better gain.
为TagLM论文提出它可以获得更好的收益。
But, you know, why everyone got really excited was that in the ELMo paper,
但是，你知道，为什么每个人都对ELMo论文感到非常兴奋，
they then showed this isn't something that you can
然后他们表明这不是你能做到的
do one-off to improve a Named Entity Recognizer,
做一次性改进命名实体识别器，
you can take these ELMo representations and use them for pretty much any NLP task,
您可以使用这些ELMo表示并将它们用于几乎任何NLP任务，
and they can be very useful and give good gains.
它们可以非常有用并且可以获得丰厚的收益。
And so, essentially why people got excited was because of the data that's in this table.
因此，人们兴奋的原因主要在于此表中的数据。
So here we're taking a whole bunch of very different tasks,
所以我们在这里采取了一大堆非常不同的任务，
so there's SQuAD question-answering, uh,
所以有SQUAD问答，呃，
there's natural language inference,
有自然语言推断，
there's semantic role labeling,
有语义角色标签，
there's co-reference, the Named Entity Recognition, doing sentiment analysis,
有共同参考，命名实体识别，进行情绪分析，
so a wide range of different NLP tasks,
所以各种不同的NLP任务，
and they have a previous state of the art system.
他们拥有先前的先进系统。
They produced their own baseline um, which is,
他们制作了自己的基线，这是，
you know, commonly sort of similar to the previous state of the art,
你知道，通常类似于以前的技术水平，
but usually actually a bit worse than
但通常实际上有点差
the current state of the art because it's
目前的技术水平，因为它
whatever simpler cleaner system that they came up with,
无论他们想出什么更简单的清洁系统，
but then they could say in each case,
但他们可以在每种情况下说，
oh, just take this system and add
哦，只需要使用这个系统并添加
ELMo vectors into the hidden representations in the middle,
ELMo向中间隐藏的表示，
and have those help you predict.
并帮助你预测。
And in general, in all cases,
一般而言，在所有情况下，
that's giving you about a three percent or so gain absolute
这让你获得大约3％左右的绝对收益
which was then producing this huge performance increase,
然后产生了巨大的性能提升，
which in all cases was moving the performance well above the previous,
在所有情况下，表现都远远超过以前，
um, state of the art system.
嗯，最先进的系统。
So you know, this sort of then made it seem like magic pixie dust,
所以你知道，这种情况让它看起来像魔法般的小精灵尘埃，
because, you know, in the stakes of NLP conference land, you know,
因为，你知道，在NLP会议的土地上，你知道，
a lot of people use to try and to come up
很多人用来尝试和提出来
with a paper for the next year that's one percent better
有一篇论文，明年会有一个百分点好
on one task and writing it up and that's
在一项任务上写下来，那就是
their big breakthrough for the year to get their new paper out.
今年他们取得新论文的重大突破。
And the idea that there's just well this set of
而且这个想法很好
this way of creating context sensitive, um,
这种创建上下文敏感的方式，嗯，
word representations and you just use them in any task,
单词表示，你只需在任何任务中使用它们，
and they'll give you around three percent and take you past the state of the art,
他们会给你大约百分之三，并带你超越最先进的，
this seemed like it was really great stuff.
这看起来真的很棒。
And so people got very excited about this and that won
所以人们对此感到非常兴奋而且赢了
the Best Paper Award at the NAACL 2018 conference.
在NAACL 2018年会议上获得最佳论文奖。
Ah, and then, a- as I sort of vaguely mentioned,
啊，然后，就像我有点模糊地提到的那样，
um, so the model that they actually used wasn't a deep stack,
嗯，所以他们实际使用的模型不是深层堆栈，
there were actually only two layers of biLSTMs,
实际上只有两层biLSTM，
but they do show this interesting result that the lower level better captures
但他们确实展示了这个有趣的结果，较低的水平更好地捕获
low-level syntax word properties
低级语法词属性
and its most useful things like part-of-speech tagging,  syntactic
及其最有用的东西，如词性标注，句法
dependencies, NER, where the top layer of
依赖关系，NER，顶层的
their language model is better for
他们的语言模型更适合
higher level semantics that is more useful for things like sentiments,
更高级别的语义，对于诸如情绪之类的事情更有用，
semantic role labeling and question answering.
语义角色标记和问答。
Um, so that seemed interesting,
嗯，这看起来很有趣，
though it'll actually be interesting to see how that panned
虽然看到它如何被淘汰实际上很有趣
out more if you had sort of more layers to play with.
如果你有更多的图层可以玩更多。
Okay. ELMo, done.
好的。 ELMo，完成了。
Um, so I'm moving right ahead.
嗯，所以我正在前进。
Um, here's something else that I just thought I should mention a little bit about,
嗯，这是我认为应该提一点的其他事情，
another piece of work that came out around the same time,
大约在同一时间出来的另一件作品，
a few months later maybe or maybe not,
几个月后，也许或许没有，
came out around the same time, uh,
大约在同一时间出来，呃，
in, in 2018, was this work on
在2018年，是这项工作
Universal Language Model Fine-tuning for text classification,
通用语言模型用于文本分类的微调，
um, or ULMfit, by Howard and Ruder.
嗯，或者是Howard和Ruder的ULMfit。
And essentially this had the same general idea of saying, Well,
基本上这有一般的想法，嗯，
what we want to do is transfer learning where we could learn a big language model, um.
我们想要做的是转移学习，我们可以学习一个大的语言模型，嗯。
A big language model,
一个很大的语言模型，
and then for our target task which might be named entity recognition.
然后是我们的目标任务，可能被命名为实体识别。
But here's text classification,
但这里的文字分类，
we can transfer this language model information and help us to do better with the task.
我们可以传输这种语言模型信息，帮助我们更好地完成任务。
And so, they proposed an architecture to do that.
因此，他们提出了一种架构来做到这一点。
And so, their architecture was,
所以，他们的架构是，
you have a big unsupervised corpus from which you train a neural language model.
你有一个很大的无监督语料库，你可以从中训练神经语言模型。
They used the deeper neural language model with three hidden layers.
他们使用了具有三个隐藏层的更深层的神经语言模型。
Um, you then fine tune
嗯，你然后微调
your neural language model on the actual domain that you're interested in working in.
你感兴趣的实际领域的神经语言模型。
So, this was sort of an extra stage that they did.
所以，这是他们所做的一个额外阶段。
And then finally, um,
最后，嗯，
you now introduce your classification objectives.
您现在介绍您的分类目标。
So, what they're going to be doing is making text classifiers.
所以，他们将要做的是制作文本分类器。
So, we're now wanting to,
所以，我们现在想要，
take this model and turn it from a language model into a text classifier.
采用此模型并将其从语言模型转换为文本分类器。
Um, but there's something that they did differently, um,
嗯，但他们做的事情有所不同，嗯，
which is in some sense,
从某种意义上说，
foreshadows the later work in transformers.
预示着变形金刚后期的工作。
So, rather than just feeding features from this into a completely different network,
因此，而不仅仅是将功能从这个网络中提供给一个完全不同的网络，
they keep using the same network but they introduce a different objective at the top.
他们继续使用相同的网络，但他们在顶部引入了不同的目标。
So, one thing you could do with this network is use
因此，使用此网络可以做的一件事就是使用
it to predict the next word as a language model.
它预测下一个单词作为语言模型。
And so at this point,
所以在这一点上，
they freeze the parameters of that softmax at the top,
他们冻结了顶部的softmax参数，
that's why it's shown in black.
这就是它以黑色显示的原因。
Um, but instead, they could stick on
嗯，相反，他们可以坚持下去
a different prediction unit where it's predicting stuff for a particular task.
一个不同的预测单元，它预测特定任务的东西。
So, it might be predicting
所以，它可能是预测
positive or negative sentiment in a text classification task or something like that.
文本分类任务中的积极或消极情绪或类似的东西。
So, in their model,
所以，在他们的模型中，
they're sort of reusing the same network but sticking on the top of that,
他们有点重复使用相同的网络，但坚持这一点，
a different layer, to do the new classification task.
一个不同的层，来做新的分类任务。
Um, they were also interested in something small,
嗯，他们也对小事感兴趣，
the sort of one GPU model of research, um,
那种研究的GPU模型，嗯，
the paper has a lot of detail, the sort of tricks
这篇论文有很多细节，那种技巧
and care and feeding of your neural models to maximize performance.
并保护和喂养您的神经模型，以最大限度地提高性能。
If you're interested in that, you could sort of look up some of the details about that.
如果您对此感兴趣，可以查看一些有关详细信息。
Um, but what they were able to show again,
嗯，但他们能再次展示的是，
was making use of this language model pre-training was
正在利用这种语言模型进行预训练
a very effective way to improve performance,
一种提高绩效的非常有效的方法，
this time for text classification.
这次是文本分类。
So, these are text classification datasets,
那么，这些是文本分类数据集，
IMDb is for sentiment,
IMDb是为了感情，
um, TREC is for topical text classification, and again,
嗯，TREC用于主题文本分类，同样，
there are preceding systems that other people have developed and they
有其他人开发的先前系统和他们
are showing that by making use of this language model pre-training,
表明通过利用这种语言模型进行预训练，
they're able to significantly improve on the state of the art of these error rates,
他们能够显着改善这些错误率的现状，
so that low is good.
所以低是好的。
They also showed another interesting result which is kind of,
他们还展示了另一个有趣的结果，
um, what you would expect or hope from doing this kind of transfer learning,
嗯，你期望或希望做这种转学习，
that what they were able to show is,
他们能够展示的是，
if you can train this neural language model on a big amount of data,
如果你可以在大量数据上训练这种神经语言模型，
that that means you will then be able to do well on
这意味着你将能够做得很好
your supervised task even when trained on pretty little data.
你的监督任务，即使是在很少的数据训练。
Um, so, here this is error rate,
嗯，所以，这是错误率，
so low is good.
这么低是好的。
So, what the- and here's the number of
那么，这是什么 - 以及这里的数量
training examples which has being done on a log scale.
培训示例已在日志范围内完成。
And so the blue line is if you're just training
如果你只是在训练，那么蓝线就是如此
a text classifier from scratch on supervised data.
从头开始对监督数据的文本分类器。
So, you need a lot of data to start to do pretty well.
因此，您需要大量数据才能开始做得很好。
Um, but if you're making use of this transfer learning, um,
嗯，但如果你正在利用这种转学习，嗯，
from a pre-trained language model,
来自预先训练的语言模型，
you can get to that you're sort of doing pretty
你可以做到你有点漂亮
well with way less, um, training examples.
好吧，嗯，训练的例子。
Essentially, an order of magnitude,
基本上，一个数量级，
less training examples will give you the same amount of performance.
较少的培训示例将为您提供相同的性能。
And the difference between these two lines corresponds to the extra,
并且这两行之间的差异对应于额外的，
um, phase that they had in the middle of theirs, um, which is,
嗯，他们在他们中间的阶段，嗯，这是，
whether you're doing this sort of extra fine tuning on your target domain,
你是否正在对目标域进行这种额外的微调，
um, it's part of your process and they found that to be pretty helpful.
嗯，这是你的过程的一部分，他们发现这是非常有帮助的。
Okay. So, that, um, is another precursor.
好的。那么，那，嗯，是另一个先驱。
Um, and so, one big part of what has happened since then,
嗯，等等，从那时起发生的事情的一大部分，
is effectively people said this is a good idea, uh,
实际上有人说这是个好主意，呃，
maybe it'll become a really really good idea if we just make things way bigger.
也许如果我们只是把事情变得更大，那将成为一个非常好的主意。
Um, so, ULMfit, um,
嗯，所以，ULMfit，嗯，
was something that you could train in one GPU day,
是你可以在一天GPU训练的东西，
sounds appealing for CS224N final projects,
听起来对CS224N最终项目很有吸引力，
remember that, um, and but well,
记得那个，嗯，但是，好吧，
then the people at OpenAI decided, well,
然后OpenAI的人决定，嗯，
we could build a pretrain language model and train it on
我们可以建立一个预训练语言模型并对其进行训练
a much larger amount of data on a much larger amount of compute,
更大量的计算量上的数据量更大，
and use about 242 GPU days and that will get a lot better, and it did.
并使用大约242个GPU天，这将会变得更好，而且确实如此。
Um, and then the people at Google said,
嗯，然后Google的人说，
well we could train a model, um,
好吧，我们可以训练一个模型，嗯，
in to 256 TPU days,
在256 TPU天，
which means maybe about double the amount of computation.
这意味着可能是计算量的两倍。
It's hard to figure out exactly,
很难弄清楚，
and that might be able to do exciting things,
这可能是令人兴奋的事情，
and that was the BERT model, and it did.
这就是BERT模型，它确实如此。
Um, and then if you're following along these things, um,
嗯，如果你跟着这些东西，嗯，
just last week, um,
就在上周，嗯，
the OpenAI people said,
OpenAI的人说，
well we can go much bigger again and we can train a model, um,
好吧，我们可以再大一点，我们可以训练一个模型，嗯，
for approximately 2,000 TPU version three days.
大约2,000 TPU版本三天。
Um, and it will be able to,
嗯，它将能够，
um, do much bigger again,
嗯，再做一点大，
a bit much better again,
再好一点，
um, and so, this is this GP2,
嗯，这就是这个GP2，
GPT-2 language model, um,
GPT-2语言模型，嗯，
which OpenAI released last week.
哪个OpenAI上周发布。
Um, and they're, they're actually very impressive results, um,
嗯，他们是，他们实际上是非常令人印象深刻的结果，嗯，
when they're showing that if you're sort of building a really,
当他们表明如果你真的在建造一个，
really huge language model over a very large amount of data.
对于非常大量的数据，真正庞大的语言模型。
And then you say language model go off and generate some text,
然后你说语言模型会生成一些文本，
on this particular topic,
在这个特定主题上，
that it can actually just do a great job of producing text.
它实际上可以很好地生成文本。
So, the way this was being do- done,
所以，这样做的方式，
was a humanist writing a couple of sentences;
是一个写一些句子的人文主义者;
in a shocking finding,
令人震惊的发现，
scientists discovered a herd of unicorns,
科学家发现了一群独角兽，
living in remote previously unexplored valley in the Andes Mountains.
生活在安第斯山脉偏远的未开发的山谷中。
Um, and so, we then,
嗯，等等，我们接着，
using our neural language model and chugging through that,
使用我们的神经语言模型，并通过它，
so that gives us context,
这给了我们背景，
and then say generate more text,
然后说生成更多文字，
and it starts to generate the scientist
它开始产生科学家
named the population after their distinctive horn,
以他们独特的号角命名人口，
Ovid's Unicorn, these four-horned,
奥维德的独角兽，这四个角，
silver-white Uni four corns were previously unknown to science.
银白色Uni四个玉米以前不为科学所知。
Um, it produces remarkably,
嗯，它产生了显着的，
um, good text or at least in the,
嗯，好文本或至少在，
in the hand-picked examples [LAUGHTER] that they showed in the tech news,
在他们在科技新闻中展示的精选示例[笑声]中，
um, it produces extremely good text.
嗯，它产生了非常好的文字。
Um, yeah so, I think one should be a little bit cautious about, um,
嗯，是的，我觉得应该有点谨慎，嗯，
that and sort of some of its random outputs actually
实际上，它的一些随机输出
aren't nearly as good but nevertheless you know,
不是很好，但你知道，
I think is is actually dramatic
我认为其实是戏剧性的
how good language models are becoming once you are training
一旦你接受培训，语言模型会变得多么好
them on long contexts as we can do with modern models on vast amounts of data, um-.
它们在很长的背景下，就像我们可以用大量数据的现代模型一样，嗯 - 。
So then, um, the OpenAI people decided
那么，嗯，OpenAI的人决定了
this language model was so good that they weren't gonna release it to the world, um,
这个语言模型非常好，他们不会把它发布到世界上，嗯，
which then got transformed into headlines of,
然后变成了头条新闻，
Elon Musk's OpenAI builds artificial intelligence so powerful,
Elon Musk的OpenAI构建了如此强大的人工智能，
it must be kept locked up for the good of humanity.
为了人类的利益，必须把它锁起来。
[LAUGHTER] Um, with the suitable pictures that always turn off at
[大笑]嗯，有合适的照片，总是关闭
these moments down the bottom of the screen, um, and,
这些时刻在屏幕的底部，嗯，和，
um, yeah I guess that was the leading even Elon Musk to be wanting to clarify and say
嗯，是的，我想这是领导甚至Elon Musk想要澄清和说
that it's not actually really that he's directing what's happening at OpenAI anymore.
他实际上并不是在指导OpenAI发生的事情。
Um, anyway, moving right along.
嗯，无论如何，向右移动。
Um, so, part of the story here is
嗯，所以，这里的部分故事是
just a scaling thing that these things have been getting bigger and bigger,
只是一个缩放的事情，这些事情越来越大，
um, but the other part of the story is that all three of
嗯，但故事的另一部分是所有三个
these are then systems that use the transformer architecture.
这些是使用变压器架构的系统。
And transformer architectures have not only being very powerful,
变压器架构不仅非常强大，
but technically had allowed scaling to much bigger sizes.
但从技术上讲，它允许扩展到更大的尺寸。
So to understand some of the rest of these, um,
所以要了解其余的一些，嗯，
we should learn more about transformers.
我们应该更多地了解变压器。
And so, I'm sort of gonna do that, um,
所以，我有点那样做，嗯，
but I mean, um, in mix of orders,
但我的意思是，嗯，混合订单，
um, our invited speaker coming Thursday uh, is, um,
嗯，我们邀请的演讲者星期四来，呃，是，嗯，
one of the authors of the transformer paper,
变压器纸的作者之一，
and he's gonna talk about transformers.
他会谈论变形金刚。
So I think what I'm gonna do is, um,
所以我想我要做的是，嗯，
say a little bit about transformers quickly,
快速说一下变压器
but not really dwell on all the details, um,
但是并没有真正详述所有细节，嗯，
but hope that it's a bit of an introduction,
但希望这是一个介绍，
and you can find out more on Thursday about the details and
你可以在周四了解更多关于细节的信息
then talk some more about the BERT model before finishing.
然后在完成之前再谈谈BERT模型。
So the motivation for transformers is essentially
所以变压器的动机本质上是
we want things to go faster so we can build bigger models,
我们希望事情变得更快，以便我们可以建立更大的模型，
and the problem as we mentioned for these, um,
和我们为这些提到的问题，嗯，
LSTM or in general any of the recurrent models is the fact that they're recurrent.
LSTM或一般的任何复发模型都是它们经常发生的事实。
You have to generate sort of one to n status time chugging through,
你必须生成一到n个状态时间，
and that means you just can't do the same kind of parallel computation, um,
这意味着你不能做同样的并行计算，嗯，
that GPUs love that you can do in things like convolutional neural networks.
那些GPU喜欢你可以做的事情，比如卷积神经网络。
But, you know, on the other hand,
但是，你知道，另一方面，
we discovered that even though, um,
我们发现即使，嗯，
these gated recurrent units like LSTMs and GRUs are great,
这些门控的经常性单位，如LSTM和GRU都很棒，
that to get really great performance out of these recurrent models,
为了从这些经常性模型中获得真正出色的性能，
we found that we wanted to- we had a problem within these long sequence lengths,
我们发现我们想要 - 在这些长序列长度内遇到问题，
and we can improve things by adding attention mechanisms.
我们可以通过增加注意机制来改进。
And so that led to the idea of- well,
所以这导致了 - 好吧，
since attention works so great,
因为注意力如此之大，
maybe we can just use attention,
也许我们可以只关注，
and we can actually get rid of the recurrent part of the model [NOISE] altogether.
我们实际上可以完全摆脱模型[NOISE]的复现部分。
And so that actually then leads to the idea of these transformer architectures,
所以这实际上导致了这些变压器架构的想法，
and the original paper on this is actually called attention is all you need,
而关于这个的原始文件实际上被称为注意力是你所需要的，
which reflects this idea of we're gonna keep the attention part,
这反映了我们要保持注意力的这个想法，
and we're getting- going to get rid of the, um,
我们要开始摆脱这个，嗯，
recurrent part, and we'll be able to build a great model.
经常性的部分，我们将能够建立一个伟大的模型。
So in the initial work,
所以在最初的工作中，
what they're doing is machine translation kind of like
他们正在做的是机器翻译之类的
the Neural Machine Translation with attention we described,
我们所描述的神经机器翻译，
but what they're wanting to do is build
但他们想要做的就是建立
a complex encoder and a complex decoder that works non-recurrently,
复杂的编码器和复杂的解码器，非循环工作，
and, um, nevertheless is able to translate sentences
然而，嗯，能够翻译句子
well by making use of lots of attention distributions.
好好利用大量的注意力分配。
And so, I wanted to say a little bit more quickly about that,
所以，我想更快地说一点，
and hopefully we'll get more of this on Thursday.
希望我们周四能得到更多。
Um, first as a- as a recommended resource,
嗯，首先作为推荐资源，
if you wanna look at, um,
如果你想看看，嗯，
home and learn more about, um,
回家了解更多关于，嗯，
the transformer architecture, there's this really great, um,
变压器架构，这真的很棒，嗯，
bit of work by Sasha Rush called The Annotated Transformer that goes through
Sasha Rush的一些工作称为The Annotated Transformer
the entire transformer paper accompanied by PyTorch code in a Jupyter Notebook,
整个变压器纸伴随着Jupyter笔记本中的PyTorch代码，
and so that can actually be a really useful thing,
所以这实际上可能是一个非常有用的东西，
but I'll go through a little bit of the basics now of how we do things.
但是我现在将介绍一下我们如何做事的一些基础知识。
So the basic idea, um,
所以基本的想法，嗯，
is that they're going to use attention everywhere to calculate things.
就是他们会到处用注意力来计算事物。
And, um, we talked before about the different kinds of
而且，嗯，我们之前谈过不同类型的
attention of the sort of multiplicative by linear attention and the little,
通过线性注意和一点点的乘法注意
um, feed-forward network additive attention.
嗯，前馈网络添加剂注意。
They kind of go for the simplest kind of attention,
它们有点像最简单的关注，
where the attention is just dot-products between two things.
注意力只是两件事之间的互补产品。
Um, but they sort of do the more comp- for various purposes,
嗯，但它们更适合各种目的，
they do the more complicated version of dot-product between two things where they have,
他们在两件事之间做了更复杂的点积，
um, when the- the things that they're looking up are
嗯，当他们正在查找的东西是
assumed to be key-value pairs, keys and values,
假设是键值对，键和值，
and so you're calculating the similarity as a dot-product between a query and the key,
所以你计算相似度作为查询和密钥之间的点积，
and then based on that,
然后基于此，
you're going to be using the vector for the corresponding value.
你将使用向量作为相应的值。
So our equation here for what we're calculating is where you are
所以我们在这里计算我们正在计算的是你的位置
looking using the softmax over query, um,
使用softmax而不是查询，嗯，
key similarities and using that to give
关键的相似之处并用它来给予
the weightings as an attention based weighting over the corresponding values.
权重作为基于注意力的权重超过相应的值。
Um, so that's the basic attention model.
嗯，这是基本的关注模型。
Um, so that add- saying it that way, um,
嗯，所以这样说吧，嗯，
adds a little bit of complexity,
增加了一点复杂性，
but sort of for the simplest part for their encoder.
但对于他们的编码器来说，这是最简单的部分。
Actually, all of the query keys and values are exactly the same.
实际上，所有查询键和值都完全相同。
They are the words, um,
他们是这些话，嗯，
that they're using as their source language, um, things.
他们使用的是他们的源语言，嗯，事情。
So, it sort of adds some complexity that isn't really there.
因此，它增加了一些并非真正存在的复杂性。
Um, okay. Um, I'll skip that.
嗯，好的。嗯，我会跳过那个。
Um, so, there are a couple of other things that they do.
嗯，他们还有其他一些事情。
One thing that they note is that, um,
他们注意到的一件事是，嗯，
the- the values you get from, um, QTK, um,
你得到的价值，嗯，QTK，嗯，
very, in variances the dimension gets large
非常，差异变大了
so that they sort of do some normalization by the size of the hidden state dimension,
这样它们就可以通过隐藏状态维度的大小进行一些归一化，
but I'll leave that out as well for details, right.
但是我会把它留给细节，对吧。
So in the encoder, um,
那么在编码器中，嗯，
everything is just our word vectors,
一切都只是我们的单词向量，
there are the queries, the keys, and the values.
有查询，键和值。
Um, and we're gonna use attention everywhere in the system.
嗯，我们将在系统的各个地方使用注意力。
Oops. Okay. So the second new idea is, well,
哎呀。好的。所以第二个新想法是，嗯，
attention is great but maybe it's bad if you only have one attention distribution,
注意力很好，但如果你只有一个注意力分配可能会很糟糕，
because you're gonna only attend to things one way.
因为你只会以某种方式处理事物。
Maybe for various users it would be great
也许对于不同的用户来说它会很棒
if you could attend from one position to various things.
如果你可以从一个位置参加各种事情。
So, if you're thinking about syntax and what we did with dependency parsers.
所以，如果您正在考虑语法以及我们使用依赖解析器做了什么。
If you're a word, you might want to attend to your headword,
如果你说的话，你可能想要关注你的标题，
but you might also wanna attend- attend to your dependent words.
但你可能也想参加 - 关注你的依赖词。
And if you happen to be a pronoun,
如果你碰巧是一个代名词，
you might want to attend to what the pronoun refers to you.
你可能想要关注代词所指的是什么。
You might want to have lots of attention.
你可能想要得到很多关注。
So they introduced this idea of multi-head attention.
所以他们引入了这种多头注意力的想法。
And so what you're doing with multi-head attention is you have,
所以你有多头注意力，你有，
um, your hidden states,
嗯，你隐藏的状态，
um, in your system,
嗯，在你的系统中，
and you map them via projection layers, um,
你通过投影层映射它们，嗯，
which are just multiplications by different W matrices as
这只是不同W矩阵的乘法
linear projections into sort of different lower dimensional spaces,
线性投影到不同的低维空间，
and then you use each of those to calculate dot-product attention,
然后你用这些来计算网点产品的注意力，
and so you can attend to different things at the same time.
所以你可以同时处理不同的事情。
And this multi-head attention was one of
这种多头注意力是其中之一
the very successful ideas of transformers that made them a more powerful architecture.
变形金刚非常成功的想法使它们成为一个更强大的架构。
Okay. Um, so, then for our complete transformer block,
好的。嗯，那么，对于我们完整的变压器块，
it's sort of then starting to build complex architectures like we sort of started seeing,
它开始构建复杂的架构，就像我们开始看到的一样，
um, the other week.
嗯，另一周。
Um, so- okay.
嗯，好吧。
Yeah. So, starting,
是啊。所以，开始，
um, from our word vectors,
嗯，从我们的单词向量，
we're kind of going to do attention to multiple different things,
我们会注意多种不同的事情，
um, and we're simultaneously gonna have
嗯，我们会同时拥有
a residual connection that short-circuits around them.
在它们周围短路的剩余连接。
Um, we're then going to sort of sum the two of these,
嗯，我们接下来要总结其中的两个，
and then they're going to do a normalization at that point.
然后他们将在那时进行标准化。
Um, I talked previously about batch normalization,
嗯，我之前谈过批量标准化，
they don't do batch normalization,
他们不进行批量标准化，
they do another variant which is layer normalization,
他们做另一种变体，即层标准化，
which is a different way of doing normalization,
这是一种不同的规范化方式，
but I'll skip that for now.
但我暂时不会这样做。
And then they sort of for one transformer block,
然后它们分为一个变压器块，
you then go after the multi-head attention,
然后你去追寻多头，
you put things through a feed-forward layer which also has a residual connection,
你把东西穿过一个也有剩余连接的前馈层，
you sum the output of those,
你总结那些的输出，
and you then again do another, um, layer normalization.
然后你又做了另一个，嗯，图层规范化。
So this is the basic transformer block that they're gonna use everywhere.
所以这是他们将在任何地方使用的基本变压器模块。
And to make their complete architectures,
并制作完整的架构，
they're then gonna sort of start stacking
然后他们会开始堆叠
these transformer blocks to produce a very deep network.
这些变压器块可以产生非常深的网络。
And in some sense,
从某种意义上说，
what has been found is that transformers performed very well.
已经发现变压器表现非常好。
But, you know, there's no free lunch,
但是，你知道，没有免费的午餐，
um, you kind of can't.
嗯，你有点不能。
You're- now, no longer getting
你 - 现在，不再了
recurrent information actually being carried along a sequence.
经常在序列中携带的经常性信息。
You've got a word at some position which can be casting attention,
你在某个位置上有一句话可以引起注意，
uh, on other words.
呃，换句话说。
So if you'd like to have information carried along in a chain,
所以，如果您想在链中传递信息，
you've sort of first of all gotta walk the first step of the chain,
你首先要走的是链条的第一步，
and then you need to have another layer
然后你需要有另一层
vertically which can walk the next step of the chain,
垂直，可以走链的下一步，
and then you need to have another layer vertically that walks the next step of the chain.
然后你需要有一个垂直的另一层，走向链的下一步。
So, you're getting rid of the recurrence along the sequence,
所以，你正在摆脱序列的复发，
but you're substituting some depth to allow things to walk along multiple hops.
但是你要用一些深度代替，以便让事情沿着多跳。
But nevertheless, that's highly advantageous in GPU architectures
但是，这在GPU架构中非常有利
because it allows you to use parallelization to calculate everything at each,
因为它允许你使用并行化来计算每个的所有内容，
um, depth at the same time. Um.
嗯，同时深度。嗯。
Maybe I'll go light on explaining this as well.
也许我会解释这个问题。
Um, so they use byte-pair encodings.
嗯，所以他们使用字节对编码。
But if you do nothing else,
但如果你什么都不做，
you just have words fed in this word vectors and you have
你只需要在这个单词向量中输入单词，就可以了
no idea whether you're at the beginning of the sentence or at the end of the sentence.
不知道你是在句子的开头还是句末。
Though, they have a message of- method of doing positional encoding which gives
虽然，他们有一个消息 - 做位置编码的方法给出
you some ideas to pro- position your word has in the sentence.
你有一些想法可以在句子中保留你的单词。
Okay. Um, so that's sort of the, um, encoder system.
好的。嗯，这就是那种编码器系统。
So from the words,
所以从话说，
they have an initial word embedding,
他们有一个初始的嵌入词，
you add in their positional encoding,
你添加他们的位置编码，
you go into one of these transformer blocks,
你进入其中一个变压器块，
and you then repeat it n times.
然后你重复n次。
So you'll have a stack of these transformer blocks.
所以你将有一堆这些变压器块。
So you're multiple times doing, um,
所以你多次这样做，嗯，
multi-head attention to other parts of the sentence, calculating values,
多头注意句子的其他部分，计算值，
feeding forward a value,
提前一个价值，
putting it through a fully-connected layer,
穿过一个完全连接的层，
and then you just sort of repeat, do attention to different places in the sentence.
然后你只是重复一遍，注意句子中的不同地方。
Get all your information,
获取所有信息，
put it through a fully connected layer,
把它穿过一个完全连接的层，
and go up, um, proceeding up deeply.
上去，嗯，深深地前进。
And and that sounds a little mysterious,
而这听起来有点神秘，
but it turns out to work just great.
但事实证明它很有效。
And the way to think about,
思考的方式，
I think is that at each stage,
我想是在每个阶段，
you can look with your multi-headed attention and various other places in the sentence,
你可以看看你的多头注意力和句子中的其他各个地方，
accumulate information, push it up to the next layer.
累积信息，将其推送到下一层。
And if you do that sort of half a dozen times,
如果你这样做了六次，
you can be starting to progressively push information along
你可以开始逐步推送信息
the sequence in either direction to calculate values that are of interest.
在任一方向上的序列来计算感兴趣的值。
Um, and the interesting thing is that these models turn out to work
嗯，有趣的是这些模型开始发挥作用
really well at sort of learning to attend the interesting things in linguistic structure.
非常善于学习参加语言结构中的有趣事物。
Um, so these are just sort of suggestive diagrams,
嗯，所以这些只是一些暗示图，
but this is looking at layer five of the transformer stack and
但这是看变压器堆栈的第五层和
seeing what words are being attended to by different attention heads.
看到不同注意力的人正在注意什么词。
So these different colors correspond to different attention heads.
所以这些不同的颜色对应不同的注意力头。
And so the sentence is,
所以句子是，
um, it is, "In this spirit,
嗯，是的，“本着这种精神，
that a majority of American governments have passed new laws since
自那以后，大多数美国政府都通过了新的法律
2009 making the registration or voting process more difficult."
2009年使登记或投票过程更加困难。“
And so what we see is sort of most of the attention heads,
所以我们看到的是大部分注意力，
uh, looking from making to making more difficult and that seems to be useful.
呃，从制作变得更加困难，这看起来很有用。
One of the attention heads seems to be looking at the word itself might be okay.
其中一个注意力的人似乎在看这个词本身可能没问题。
Um, then the other ones are sort of looking a bit at laws and at 2009.
嗯，那么其他的有点看法和2009年。
So it's sort of picking out the arguments, um,
所以它有点挑选出来的论点，嗯，
and modifiers and making in a syntax kind of like way.
和修饰语，并在语法中做出类似的方式。
Um, interestingly, for pronouns,
嗯，有趣的是，对于代词，
attention heads appear to learn to be able to look back to reference.
注意头似乎学会了回顾参考。
So the law will never be perfect,
所以法律永远不会是完美的，
but its application should be just that one attention head it for its,
但它的应用应该只是一个注意力为它，
is looking at what its is modifying in the application.
正在研究它在应用程序中正在修改的内容。
But another attention head,
但另一个关注头，
the its is looking strongly at what its refers back to as the law.
它正在强烈关注它所引用的法律。
So that seems kind of cool.
所以这看起来很酷。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
And so then, for the rest of the model, um,
那么，对于模型的其余部分，嗯，
there's then some more complexity for how to use
然后有一些更复杂的使用方法
the transformers decoder to give you a full neural machine translation system.
变形金刚解码器为您提供完整的神经机器翻译系统。
But I think maybe I will skip that and go
但我想也许我会跳过那个去
on and say a bit about BERT in my remaining minutes.
在我剩下的几分钟内谈一谈BERT。
Okay. So, um, the latest and greatest contextual
好的。所以，嗯，最新最好的背景
word representations to help you flow your tasks have been these BERT vectors,
帮助您完成任务的单词表示一直是这些BERT向量，
where BERT is Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers.
其中BERT是变压器的双向编码器表示。
And so essentially, it's using the encoder from a transformer network.
基本上，它正在使用变压器网络中的编码器。
Uh, this deep multi-headed attention stack to calculate, um,
呃，这个深入的多头注意力堆栈来计算，嗯，
a representation of a sentence and saying,
一个句子的代表和说，
"That's a great all-purpose representation of a sentence that you can use for tasks.
“这是一个很好的通用表示，你可以用来完成任务。
Be it named entity recognition or SQuAD question answering."
无论是实体识别还是SQuAD问答。“
And so there's actually an interesting new idea that these people had.
所以这些人实际上有一个有趣的新想法。
And that well, their idea was well standard language models are
好吧，他们的想法是很好的标准语言模型
unidirectional and that's useful
单向的，这很有用
because it gives you a probability distribution of a language model.
因为它为您提供了语言模型的概率分布。
But it's bad because you'd like to be able to do
但这很糟糕，因为你希望能够做到
prediction from both sides to understand word meaning and context.
从双方预测来理解词义和语境。
There's a second choice, um,
还有第二个选择，嗯，
which is you can kind of do bidirectional models when you incorporate,
当你合并时，你可以做双向模型，
um, information in both ways.
嗯，两种方式的信息。
But that sort of has problems as well,
但那种问题也存在，
because then you get crosstalk.
因为那时你得到串扰。
Um, and so if you run a BiLSTM,
嗯，如果你运行BiLSTM，
and then you merge the representations by
然后你合并表示
concatenation and then feed them into the next layer.
连接然后将它们提供给下一层。
When you're running the next layer,
当你运行下一层时，
the forward LSTM will have already gotten
前锋LSTM已经得到了
information about the future from the first layer.
有关第一层未来的信息。
Um, so it sort of, um,
嗯，好吧，嗯，
ends up with words that have already seen the future themselves.
结束了已经看过未来的话。
So you have this sort of complex non-generative model.
所以你有这种复杂的非生成模型。
Um, so somehow, they wanted to do things a bit differently,
嗯，不知何故，他们想做的事情有点不同，
so they can have bidirectional context without words being able to see themselves.
因此，他们可以拥有双向上下文，而无需言语。
And the idea that they came up with is well,
他们提出的想法很好，
we're gonna train things with a transformer encoder.
我们要用变压器编码器训练东西。
But what we're gonna do is mask out some of the words in the sentence,
但我们要做的是掩盖句子中的一些词，
like, maybe we'll mask here store and gallon.
比如，也许我们会在这里掩盖商店和加仑。
And then, so our language mod- our language modelling like
然后，我们的语言模型 - 我们的语言建模就像
objective will no longer be
目标将不再是
a true language model that's sort of generating a probability of a sentence,
一种真正的语言模型，它会产生一个句子的概率，
um, which is standardly done by working from left to right,
嗯，这是从左到右工作的标准做法，
but it will instead be a Mad Libs style fill in the blank objective.
但它将成为一个疯狂的Libs风格填补空白的目标。
So you'll see this context,
所以你会看到这个背景，
which will be literally,
这将是字面意思，
"The man went to the mask to buy a mask of milk."
“那个男人去面具买了一口牛奶。”
And your, what's your training objective is to say,
而你的，你的训练目标是什么，
try and predict what this word is,
试着预测这个词是什么，
which you can do with a cross entropy loss to the extent that you don't guess store.
你可以做到交叉熵损失到你猜不到存储的程度。
And then, it will be trying to guess what this word is and you want to let guess gallon.
然后，它将试图猜测这个词是什么，你想让加仑猜。
So you're training a model,
所以你正在训练一个模型，
um, to fill in these blanks.
嗯，填写这些空白。
Um, and the rate at which they blank words is essentially one word in seven,
嗯，他们空白单词的比率基本上是七分之一，
and they discuss how this is a trade-off.
他们讨论了如何进行权衡。
Because if you blank too few words,
因为如果你空白的话太少了，
it gets very expensive to train.
训练非常昂贵。
And if you blank many words,
如果你空白很多话，
well you've blanked out most of the context of a word,
好吧，你已经消除了一个词的大部分背景，
and that means it's not very useful for training,
这意味着它对培训来说不是很有用，
and they found about sort of one in seven seemed to work pretty well for them.
他们发现七分之一的人似乎对他们很有效。
But what they want to argue is, um,
但他们想要争辩的是，嗯，
that for the OpenAI's GPT,
对于OpenAI的GPT，
which is also a transformer model.
这也是一个变压器模型。
It's a sort of a classic language model working from
这是一种经典的语言模型
left to right and so you only get left context.
从左到右，所以你只能得到左上下文。
Um, for the BERT language model,
嗯，对于BERT语言模型，
sorry, the ELMo language model that's shown up at the top.
对不起，ELMo语言模型显示在顶部。
Um, well, they're running a left to right language model and they're running,
嗯，他们正在运行一个从左到右的语言模型，他们正在运行，
um, right to left language models.
嗯，从右到左的语言模型。
So in some sense, um,
所以在某种意义上，嗯，
they have context from both sides.
他们有双方的背景。
But these two language models are trained completely independently
但是这两种语言模型是完全独立训练的
and then you're just sort of concatenating their representations, um, together.
然后你只是将他们的表现联系起来，嗯，在一起。
So there's no sense in which we're actually kind of having a model that's jointly
因此，我们实际上并没有意识到共同拥有一个模型
using context from both sides at the time though that the pre-trained,
使用双方的背景，虽然预先训练，
um, contextual word representations are built.
嗯，建立了语境词表示。
So their hope is using inside a transformer model
所以他们希望在变压器模型中使用
this trick of blanking out words,
这个消隐的伎俩，
and predicting it using the entire context will allow them to use two-sided context,
并使用整个上下文预测它将允许他们使用双面上下文，
and be much more effective.
并且更加有效。
And that's what they seem to show, um.
这就是他们似乎表现出来的，嗯。
There's one other complication and,
还有一个并发症，
I mean, I'll show later.
我的意思是，我稍后会说。
Um, this last complication is a bit useful,
嗯，这最后的复杂功能有点用处，
but it's sort of not really essential to their main idea,
但它对他们的主要想法并不是很重要，
was that they thought,
是他们想的，
one of the, one of the goals in their head was clearly to be able to
其中一个，他们头脑中的一个目标显然是能够的
have this be useful for things like question answering,
这有用于问答，
um, tasks, or, um,
嗯，任务，或者，嗯，
natural language inference tasks,
自然语言推理任务，
and their relationships between, um, two sentences.
和他们之间的关系，嗯，两句话。
So, their idea was, well,
所以，他们的想法是，好吧，
one good objective is this fill in the blank word objective which is,
一个好的目标是填写空白词目标，即：
sort of, like language modeling objective.
有点像语言建模目标。
But they thought it would be useful to have a second objective
但他们认为有第二个目标是有用的
where you're predicting relationships between sentences.
你在哪里预测句子之间的关系。
So, they secondly have a loss function which is, um,
所以，他们其次有一个损失函数，嗯，
let's have two sentences where
我们有两句话在哪里
the sentences might be two successive sentences in the text,
句子可能是文中两个连续的句子，
or a sentence followed by a random sentence from somewhere else.
或者从其他地方跟随句子的句子。
And we want to train the system to predict when you've,
我们希望训练系统预测你的时间，
seeing an- a correct next sentence versus a random sentence.
看到一个正确的下一句与一​​个随机句。
And so you're also training a loss based on this next sentence prediction task.
因此，您还要根据下一个句子预测任务来训练损失。
And so it'll be something like: The man went to the store.
所以它会是这样的：男人去了商店。
He bought a gallon of milk.
他买了一加仑牛奶。
You're meant to predict true is the next sentence,
你的意思是预测下一句是真的，
um: The man went to the store.
嗯：那个男人去了商店。
Penguins are flightless.
企鹅不会飞。
You're meant to say false.
你的意思是假的。
This isn't the next sentence.
这不是下一句话。
And so they're simultaneously also,
所以他们同时也是，
um, training with this representation.
嗯，用这种表示进行训练。
So, what they end up looks, looks like this.
所以，他们看起来最终看起来像这样。
Um, so, they have,
嗯，他们有，
um, for the input,
嗯，输入，
they'll have a pair of sentences.
他们会有一对句子。
My dog is cute.
我的狗很可爱。
Um, separator.
嗯，分隔符。
He likes playing.
他喜欢打球。
Um, the words are represented as word pieces like we talked about last week.
嗯，这些单词就像我们上周谈到的那样。
Um, so there's a token embedding for each word piece.
嗯，所以每个单词都有一个标记嵌入。
Um, then there's a positional embedding for
嗯，然后有一个位置嵌入
each word piece which is gonna be summed with the token embedding.
每个单词块将与令牌嵌入相加。
And then finally, there's a segment embedding for each word piece which is simply
然后最后，每个单词的片段嵌入都是简单的
whether it comes from the first sentence or
是来自第一句话还是
the second sentence before or after the separator.
分隔符之前或之后的第二句。
So, you're summing those three things together to get the token representations.
所以，你将这三个东西总结在一起以获得令牌表示。
And then you're going to use those in a transformer model
然后你将在变压器模型中使用它们
where you will have losses to the extent that you can't predict the masked words.
如果您无法预测蒙面语言，那么您将面临损失。
And then your binary prediction function as to whether there's
然后你的二进制预测功能是否存在
a correct next sentence or not which is the training architecture.
一个正确的下一句话是否是训练架构。
Okay. So, it's a transformer as before,
好的。所以，它像以前一样是变压器，
it's trained on Wikipedia plus the BookCorpus.
它在维基百科和BookCorpus上接受过培训。
And they built two models.
他们建造了两个模型。
Um, the Base-BERT model was a twelve layer transformer.
嗯，Base-BERT模型是十二层变压器。
And so this corresponded to what the previous transformer paper had used, right?
所以这对应于以前的变压器纸张使用的，对吧？
Those two layer transformer blocks repeated six times gave you 12 layers with 768 hidden,
这两层变压器块重复六次，给你12层，隐藏768层，
um, dimension hidden states and 12 heads for the multi-head attention.
嗯，尺寸隐藏状态和12头为多头注意。
And then they went bigger,
然后他们变大了，
um, and trained BERT-Large which is,
嗯，训练有素的BERT-Large，
sort of, double the number of layers,
排序，加倍层数，
bigger hidden states, even more attention heads.
更大的隐藏状态，更多的注意力。
Um, and training these on,
嗯，并训练这些，
um, pods of TPUs.
嗯，TPU的豆荚。
Um, so, first of all, you're training, um,
嗯，首先，你正在训练，嗯，
on this basis for masked words and,
在此基础上使用蒙面语言，
um, next sentence or not.
嗯，下一句话与否。
Um, so then what they wanted to say was this pre-trained model,
嗯，那么他们想说的是这个预先训练过的模型，
um, evaluated on these losses and masked language model and next sentence prediction.
嗯，评估这些损失和掩盖语言模型和下一句话预测。
Um, we could then take this model,
嗯，我们可以拿这个型号，
fr- freeze most of its what weak. No, sorry, that's wrong.
冻结它的大部分弱点。不，对不起，那是错的。
We could take this model, um,
我们可以采取这种模式，嗯，
pre-trained and it would be incredibly useful for various different tasks.
经过预先培训，对于各种不同的任务非常有用。
We could use it for named entity recognition,
我们可以用它来命名实体识别，
question answering, natural language inference et cetera.
问答，自然语言推理等。
And the way we're going to do it, is kind of,
而我们要做的方式，有点像，
doing the same thing as the ULMFit model did.
做与ULMFit模型相同的事情。
We're not just going to say here's our,
我们不只是说这里是我们的，
here's a contextual word representation like ELMo did.
这是像ELMo那样的上下文单词表示。
Instead, what we're gonna say is just keep on using this,
相反，我们要说的就是继续使用它，
keep on using this um,
继续使用这个，
transformer network that we trained as a, sort of,
变压器网络，我们训练成一种，
language model, but fine tune it for a particular task.
语言模型，但为特定任务微调。
So, you're now going to run this transformer
所以，你现在要运行这个变压器
calculating representations for a particular task.
计算特定任务的表示。
And what we're going to change is we're going to remove the very top-level prediction.
而我们要改变的是我们将取消最高级别的预测。
The bits that predict the mass language model and next sentence prediction.
预测大众语言模型和下一句预测的位。
And we're going to substitute on it,
而我们将替代它，
on top, um, a final prediction layer that's appropriate for the task.
在顶部，嗯，一个适合任务的最终预测层。
So, if our task is SQuAD question answering,
那么，如果我们的任务是SQUAD问题回答，
our final prediction layer will be predicting start of span and end of span,
我们的最终预测层将预测跨度的开始和跨度的结束，
kind of, like when we saw DrQA a couple of weeks ago.
就像我们几周前看到DrQA时那样。
If what we're doing is the NER task,
如果我们正在做的是NER任务，
our final prediction layer will be predicting
我们的最终预测层将是预测
the net- named entity recognition class of each token just like a standard NER system.
每个令牌的网名实体识别类就像标准的NER系统一样。
Okay, um, and so they built this system and tested it on a whole bunch of data sets.
好的，嗯，所以他们构建了这个系统，并在一大堆数据集上进行了测试。
Um, one of the main things they tested on was
嗯，他们测试的主要内容之一是
this GLUE data set which has a whole bunch of tasks.
这个GLUE数据集有很多任务。
A lot of the tasks, they're,
很多任务，他们是，
uh, natural language inference tasks.
呃，自然语言推理任务。
And I've kept saying that phrase all of this lecture but I haven't really defined it.
而且我一直在说这个讲座的所有内容，但我还没有真正定义它。
So, with a natural language inference you're given two sentences
因此，通过自然语言推断，您将获得两个句子
like: Hills and mountains are especially sanctified in Jainism.
喜欢：丘陵和山脉在耆那教中特别成圣。
And then you can write a hypothesis on: Jainism hates nature.
然后你可以写一个假设：耆那教讨厌自然。
And what you're meant to say is,
而你的意思是，
whether the hypothesis, um,
是否假设，嗯，
follows from the premise,
从前提出发，
contradicts the premise, or has no relation to the premise.
矛盾的前提，或与前提无关。
So, that's a three-way classification.
所以，这是一个三方分类。
And so here it contradicts the premise.
所以这里与前提相矛盾。
Um, there are various other tasks such as this linguistic acceptability task.
嗯，还有其他各种任务，例如这种语言可接受性任务。
Um, but if we look at these, um, GLUE tasks.
嗯，但如果我们看看这些，嗯，GLUE的任务。
Um, these are showing the Pre-OpenAI State Of The Art.
嗯，这些都展示了Pre-OpenAI的艺术状态。
How well, um, ELMo works.
嗯，ELMo的效果如何。
How well OpenAI GPT works,
OpenAI GPT的工作情况如何
and then how well do small and large BERT models work.
然后小型和大型BERT模型的工作情况如何。
And effectively, what you're finding is,
实际上，你所发现的是，
um, that the OpenAI GPT was so,
嗯，OpenAI GPT是这样的，
you know, pretty good.
你知道，非常好。
It showed actually good advances on most of these tasks.
它显示了大多数这些任务的实际进展。
For many, but not all of them that broke the previous state of the art,
对许多人来说，但并非所有人都破坏了以前的艺术水平，
showing the power of these contextual language models.
展示这些语境语言模型的力量。
But the bidirectional form of BERT's prediction just seemed much better again.
但BERT预测的双向形式似乎再好不过了。
So, going from this line to this line you're getting depending on
所以，从这一行到这一行你依赖于
the task about two percent better performance.
任务性能提高2％。
And so the BERT people actually did their experiments carefully.
因此，BERT人员实际上是在仔细进行实验。
So, these models are pretty comparable in terms of size,
所以，这些模型在尺寸方面非常可比，
but the bidirectional context seems to really help.
但双向背景似乎真的有帮助。
And then what they found was,
然后他们发现了，
well, by going to just a bigger model,
好吧，通过去一个更大的模型，
again, you could get another big lift in performance.
再次，你可以获得另一个性能提升。
And so you're getting for many of the tasks about
因此，您将完成许多任务
another two percent lift in performance going into the bigger model.
进入更大型号的性能再提高2％。
So, this really produced super-strong results.
所以，这真的产生了超强的结果。
And in general, um, people have found,
总的来说，嗯，人们发现，
um, that BERT continues to give super strong results.
嗯，BERT继续给出超强的结果。
So, if I return back to my ConLL NER task,
所以，如果我回到我的ConLL NER任务，
we had ELMo giving you 92,2,
我们让ELMo给你92,2，
um, and you, sort of,
嗯，你，有点像，
continue to get gains.
继续获得收益。
So, BERT Base gets you to 92,4 and BERT Large takes you to 92,8.
因此，BERT Base将你带到92,4，BERT Large带你到92,8。
Though in, um, truth in, truth in description,
虽然在，嗯，真相，真实的描述，
there is now a system of beats BERT Large on NER which is actually a character-level,
现在有一个在NER上击败BERT Large的系统，它实际上是一个角色级别，
um, transformer language model from Flair.
嗯，Flair的变形语言模型。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
this continued over to a lot of other things.
这继续到很多其他的事情。
So, on SQuAD 1,1, um,
那么，在SQuAD 1,1上，嗯，
BERT immediately just outperformed
BERT立即表现优异
everything else that people have been working on for SQuAD for ages.
人们为SQUAD工作多年的其他一切。
In particular, what was especially dramatic, um,
尤其是那些特别引人注目的，嗯，
was the sing- a single BERT model, um,
是单一的BERT模型，嗯，
beat everything else that had been done previously on SQuAD version 1,1,
击败之前在SQuAD 1,1版上完成的所有其他功能，
even though they could also show that an
即使他们也可以表明一个
ensemble of BERT models could give further good, um, performance gains.
BERT模型的集合可以提供更好的，嗯，性能提升。
Um, and as I've mentioned before,
嗯，正如我之前提到的，
essentially if you look at the SQuAD 2,0, um,
基本上如果你看看SQuAD 2,0，嗯，
leaderboard, all of the top ranked systems,
排行榜，所有排名靠前的系统，
um, are using BERT one place or another.
嗯，正在使用BERT这个或那个地方。
Um, and so that,
嗯，等等，
sort of, led into this,
有点，导致这个，
sort of, new world order, um, that, okay,
那种，新的世界秩序，嗯，好吧，
it seems like the state of NLP now is to,
现在似乎是NLP的状态，
if you want to have the best performance,
如果你想拥有最好的表现，
you want to be using
你想要使用
these deep pre-trained transformer stacks to get the best performance.
这些深度预先训练好的变压器堆栈可以获得最佳性能。
And so this is, sort of, making,
所以这就是，制作，
um, NLP more like vision.
嗯，NLP更像是视觉。
Because really vision for five years has had
因为五年的真实愿景已经存在
these deep pre-trained neural network stacks, um, like ResNets.
这些深度预训练的神经网络堆栈，嗯，像ResNets。
Where for most vision tasks what you do is you take a pre-trained ResNet,
对于大多数视力任务而言，您所做的就是接受预先培训的ResNet，
and then you fine tune a layer at the top to
然后你微调顶部的一层
do some classification tasks you're interested in.
做一些你感兴趣的分类任务。
And this is, sort of, now, um,
这就是，现在，嗯，
starting to be what's happening in NLP as well.
开始成为NLP中正在发生的事情。
That you can do the same thing by downloading
你可以通过下载做同样的事情
your pre-trained BERT and fine tuning it to do some particular performance task.
你经过预先训练的BERT并对其进行微调以完成一些特定的性能任务。
Okay, um, that's it for today and more on
好的，嗯，今天就是这样，还有更多
transformers on Thursday [NOISE].
变形金刚周四[NOISE]。